hello all welcome to the junkyard love
podcast it's me your host jacob bryans
i'm happy you
are here this is episode number two in
the sense making sickness
series my goal with this series
was essentially to solve the problem or
try to
shine a light on the problem or put a
magnifying glass or even just one point
towards solving or figuring out or
talking about the things that are
happening in the world
what i mean by that is just kind of the
the overall madness you know the
the inability to make sense the
inability to have the correct
conversations
um are descends into weird chaos
our group thinking our tribalism our
echo chambers
our interaction and intertwining with
social media and our social media
avatars and news media and what news
media is and
just this whole kind of conundrum that i
think over the last few years especially
and certainly with the uh the kova 19
situation and the lockdowns and all that
really shines a light on the fact that
there is a something going on
in the world at this moment it's um
or in our world even in our reality
in the life that we live as americans or
just people in the western side of the
world
um though the pandemic effects
worldwide of course i think that we're
getting to
an influx point
of kind of a
the next stage of what we need to be
doing of how we're going to be
organizing um as a culture
in forming forming new unions or
fixing what a union means or
um you know
but the first episode
i had just pages and pages of notes i
had been working for
for a couple months on this basically
compiling any
random thoughts or i'm listening to
podcast interviews or i'm listening to
lectures or i'm reading books and things
that things that would stand out to me i
would write down i would jot down the
notes
and then i would basically look at the
pages of notes
and then try to solve or fit together
you know okay what does this all mean
what is how does this intertwine
together
what's going on here and how could i
form it into words that somehow make
sense and make it to where we can change
our actions as individuals to be
moving towards the path of this
thing we have here you know this
civilization continuing the
civilization prospering and people um
feeling good and happy and wholesome and
fulfilled in their lives
um episode two
you know i didn't even plan for this
episode to be part of the sense making
sickness series
it's things that uh my friend abrielle
and i talk about
regardless we kind of send long texts
back and forth to each other or we'll
watch our own behaviors or we'll observe
how weird we're being on social media or
our social media addictions or
the way that we group think the way that
we catch our own biases and
and things of that matter and this
conversation just kind of opened up
right away
into some concepts that i have been
writing about and
trying to think about and trying to
figure out ways to present
you know through the podcast or through
my youtube channel or or any of these
things that facilitate my voice out to
the world
just something how can i help us wrap
our heads around
this bigger conversation what is this
bigger conversation
why are we not getting along so well why
are we
um arguing why are we making so many
bad other movements why are we um
you know struggling to find
homeostasis again it just feels like
there's so much
division there's so much inability to
connect
and you know i think a lot of it we
touch on in in this episode a lot of it
we kind of point out you know the
the effects of technology and the
effects of um
this second overlay of reality that
we've been living um
towards the end i talk about uh eric
some of eric weinstein's concepts around
the wwe reality that we've been living
in the
the k-fabe um amp guard
larping version of
working a a community
and a a governmental system where we're
kind of doing the illusioned version
of how to operate these
these structures rather than actually
doing them so
there is something interesting going on
um i i will end this
this intro here we'll get going this is
the sense making series
sense making sickness series
and i don't claim to be any sort of
professional
abrial doesn't claim to be any sort of
you know harvard law degree person
she has her own expertise and her own
levels of intelligence which definitely
greatly adds to this but neither of us
are um
you know i i have no phds i am i am a dj
and i do yoga you know i'm not claiming
to be
absolute or entirely correct um i'm not
claiming that i know things that other
people
don't i'm not trying to downplay other
people's ideas
i'm just trying to really stumble
through what i
feel may be going on what i what i'm
seeing in my own life and what seems to
make sense to me you know as
a creative artistic thinker these things
are what enthrall me i i
am fascinated by the the
the concept of being able to see things
before they happen
or um view things from an outside
perspective and hopefully help
facilitate or usher um you know
critical critical thought really
um towards the importance of of these
things so
again i'm i have no grandiose grandiose
ideas that i am
some sort of legend who solved all the
world's problems i don't even think we
really even solved any problems here i
think we just kind of propose a couple
perspectives that are worth
contemplating
that i think that we all as participants
in this human experience
should be contemplating so i mean no
offense to anybody
if there's anybody any of these groups
that you
identify with in this podcast that are
mentioned and used as examples
if you know me or you're familiar with
my work i think i hope it's clear at
this point that i i have no ill
intent i just simply want to help so
that's what this is
hopefully this helps hopefully this
helps you spark some ideas of your own
hopefully this helps you
even if you completely disagree with
everything that i said like cool make a
video
about it and put it out to the world and
you know we can all make sense of the
world a little bit better and now we're
one step closer to
understanding what's really going on
here so without further ado
this is the sense making sickness series
part two with abrielle dunn
um my note is a majority of the human
experience
is relaying and relating to people and i
don't feel like we're doing that
um and that just comes from
i was thinking about conversations with
you and conversations i have with
other people and then conversations i
hear about that other people are having
and when i talk to you when i talk to a
couple other people in my life
you know i have a close circle and i'm
really particular about who i talk to
and what i talk to people about
and so i like conversations
that we're conveying emotion
and relating to each other and like when
you and i talk
it's like how are you feeling and how
are you getting through this thing and
how are you experiencing this even when
we're talking about
podcasts or work or things like that
it's the feeling behind it
and how we're getting through it it's
not just like a surface level
this thing happened right and i'm
noticing that when
a lot of the differences that are
happening between people politically and
just every like whenever you it seems
like whenever you get into a
conversation with someone there's an
argument or or friction or something
like that
and we all can relate to each other
on a human level and i feel like we're
forgetting that
and so a lot of the conversation is like
what's going on in your life how i'm
working and it's like
but how do you really feel and how do
you feel about those things and i just
feel like there's that
there's not that level of relating to
people and i
as humans you know a lot of our
um experience is storytelling that's
that's how a lot of human history has
happened
just a lot of storytelling and relaying
stories to people and relating
like a lot of how we build ourselves
is comparison and
trying other people's personalities on
and seeing what we like seeing what we
don't like
and so i i think a lot a lot of that
growth
that i experience in myself comes from
relating to other people
you were working doing this how did that
make you feel
how did like you were very stressed did
it how did it affect you how did you
deal with that stress that kind of stuff
rather than i have a job and
you know someone might say either i like
it or i don't and that's kind of what
you get from it
or you know i voted for this person they
don't even say i like them i don't it's
just like
you just get friction you don't really
get any um
feeling or human emotion behind that
stuff
and so i always just think about
what why aren't we having the
conversations where we're
exploring ourselves as people rather
than
you know just surface level don't have
anything to talk about
yeah i think this that's a really dope i
i like that i'm glad that you wrote that
down
because i is when we're talking
you know when humans are interacting
we're trying to communicate something
much deeper than the words we're trying
to
we're trying to facilitate with our
mouth movements
um the building of
meaning or epiphany within the other
person
you're trying to strike within them as
you're talking
here's what i mean here's what i here's
what i'm feeling inside
but then there's it there but that's not
with everybody like that's how
that that's kind of how it feels how it
should feel how how the authentic
conversation should feel
but then there's this other version of
conversation that is
um it's it's like the illusion of having
the correct conversation
it's like this here's
here's what you do when you say someone
and i'm going to be good at that or
here's what you do
when you talk to someone you
make sure they know what group you're in
really quick so they know that you're
one of the good guys
right like it's it's like instead of
actually just opening our chests up and
trying to find way
in in allowing the first
instance of talking to someone or
meeting someone to be like fully trusted
like i trust you like i'm giving you the
benefit of doubt before i ever know you
it's almost like we walk up to each
other um
with
with our guard up in a sense like we
don't
like we we have i mean i don't want to
generalize it the word ego is just so
beat to a pulp it's almost confusing at
this point but
there is something like we approach as
a character or a character of our of our
own self like we
we are meeting people and talking via
our avatars
rather than our actual lived inner
experience
does that correlate all to what you're
saying it it definitely does
and i think a huge part of bonding with
a person
and actually finding a connection with a
person is letting that down
and expressing how you because you know
when you're talking to someone
one of the first times if it's the first
conversation
one of the first times you genuinely
feel like oh i can connect with this
person
is when you both agree on something or
you know i'm working i'm really stressed
it's really hard right now
and the person you're talking to says oh
man i'm really stressed too
i relate to that i haven't even done for
example i haven't even done my laundry
and then i hear other people i haven't
done my laundry either and then we're
like oh
girl i see you yep i did it yeah we
yeah we connect and it's just because
it's that human emotion that you can
connect with you understand you relate
to that person and so when we're talking
about things number one that we don't
understand
like politics and stuff i'm not gonna
get into a political
economic debate or anything like that
because i just don't i can pay attention
but
you know i don't understand the inner
workings of anything that's going on
so you know when you say this person's
made this choice in office i'm just like
you know i don't really until
yeah i mean i i i try to care but it's
just like it's just
it's not my job and it's not something
i'm involved in it's not one of the
things that i choose to
focus on i'm not researching it every
day and so i just don't really relate
you know when someone if if there is
someone who is really into politics
this person is doing this thing did you
see did you see this person oh it's
gonna affect this and all this kind of
stuff and just no i don't and i don't
yeah okay yeah i i sorry did i get you
off keep going no no no go ahead
um yeah i'm so so what popped in my head
actually i just
very recently i think it was literally
last night i had an interaction with
someone who
um i i get along with it totally fine um
we're not very similar at all but we get
along totally fine and
um just casually yesterday i asked um
oh hey you're gonna watch the super bowl
on sunday you've got any super bowl
plans you know just kind of the small
talk thing and uh
his response was nah i'm gonna take the
knee on that one
i've been boycotting that thing for
years and he kind of goes off on a
little a little spiel
and
it's interesting because i instantly saw
oh for me to have like if i want to have
an
actual conversation with him like a an
open
like let's let's express like how i
actually feel let's be authentic to
myself let's stand up for things that i
believe in let's explain to this person
things that i know that he may not know
um so then we can almost problem solve
we can connect we can find ways to
connect because
i didn't agree instantly with with his
comments about um you know
you know people taking the knee or
whatever because
because it's like within what he said
was this whole like
like back door like this whole explosion
waiting to happen
and that's kind of like how a lot of our
conversations have gotten right
especially when it's when it's politics
or anything that's
that they give into that political lens
um or you know the news media is
pointing cameras out and saying this is
important look at this this is what
everybody should argue about and fight
about
so me i basically chose to
like okay you know basically say very
little like oh okay yeah yeah yeah
that's pretty crazy you know i don't
know
just basically not interact with him
fully because
i i started with friendly right i
started with with like hey you got any
plans you know like you gonna are you
gonna hang out with your wife and you
know have some nachos and watch super
bowl like cool i hope you have a good
weekend whatever
but we throw up these like
there's a lot of like sentences that are
said nowadays that
indicate hey i'm team wilkistan i'm team
magastan i'm team
anti-knee i'm team knee like what all
these different things
that we're going through as a culture
that are very shining light on
they become too much they become these
like ticking time bombs of conversation
and so we're
we're self editing ourselves where you
know if i have if
if i have 65 interactions like that
where i'm just trying to have this small
talk i'm just saying hey i hope you have
a good weekend like oh what are you up
to oh you're gonna go kayaking that
sounds awesome have a good time
like if i get shut down too many times
by that
by people going like i ain't going
kayaking like i don't support the kayaks
because they're sold
what i don't know whatever like
so so i get okay so trying to wind it
back in but
so has have conversations have
authentic conversations become so
complicated
because we are coming from different
levels of not only meaning within
within but um
just information like the amount of like
i'm not trying to invalidate what he was
saying like he might have
seriously listened to 12 hours a day for
the last six
six years of information that supports
his cause and why why it's correct and
why it's very wrong to him
and i don't know i haven't listened to
the same things as him so we're all very
we're educated in different ways of our
own misinformations
that that's been given to us so um
i think that um i think you're right
and that we come to all situations sort
of with
not necessarily a mask just with a
little bit of hesitation
not really sure how much i should relate
to you where you stand are you the type
of person who when i say i like blue
you're going to just
throw up in arms that red is the right
color or something like that
um or will you be okay that like there's
a lot of colors on the spectrum i've
chosen blue
it's okay or do we not have to talk
about how do we feel about the color
that kind of thing and it's a very
that's a very uh
vague example but um
yeah i feel like it's also i don't know
i'm very vocal about how how much i
am aware of myself and i'm i'm very
um i say i'm very emotionally
intelligent but i think what i
am is just very conscious of myself and
i don't want to say i'm self-conscious
but i'm conscious of myself
and i under i think about the way i say
things the words i say
um and it's just when you
talk to somebody i don't know how
conscious of yourself
you are and so can i talk to you about
the way i'm feeling about what's going
on can i talk to you about you know like
just bringing it back to politics the
only politician i really pay attention
to is
tulsi tulsi gabbard because i love her
and
yeah one of the things that i really
like about her
is that she breaks it down from you know
there are all these
policies and topics to talk about but
like do you love your family
do you want the best for your family do
you when you go to school do you want a
good education
when you you know get sick do you want
to be able to get treatment
if your mother gets sick and she's gonna
die do you want her to be able to get
treatment it's
just like those kinds of things and
she's like we need to develop this
baseline as humans
and then figure out how we can go
forward and it takes compromise and it
takes this and that but
that's where i feel like you know people
get up in arms this thing just happened
and
you know this person released i don't
know
it's hard for me to even like i'll just
say something and i know nothing about
it so
but just like this person released this
tax plan and it's
gonna make this this and this happen and
oh my god it's an outrage and these
things like that and i'm just like i
number one i don't even know what that
means
number two i haven't researched it
enough to even know if what you're
saying is true
so i don't know if i should agree with
you not agree with you listen to you
trust what you're saying where did you
get your information
that's number two and number three like
what does it
mean for people like how did it how's it
affecting me
is it something that i want is it one of
the baseline foundational things that i
want
is it something that's going around
something to be like sneaky
and you know i just don't i don't
understand these things enough and i
feel like
a lot of these conversations are
happening that we just don't understand
and people get really defensive and they
don't take the time to understand
and we're not relating to people
when we have these conversations that we
have all this friction and we bump heads
i'm trying to take a step back and be
like
why do you feel this way that you feel
why is this person
so up in arms about something i don't
even think they understand fully
definitely i don't understand it fully
if i don't understand it fully i can't
imagine how much this person understands
it
and just like
what is going to make you feel
so hard-headed or stubborn about feeling
this way like why are you so passionate
about this thing where does it come from
i want to understand those things and i
feel like that's definitely not the
conversation we're having
people are just so upset about this is
happening on this side this is happening
on this side
whatever's going on i've honestly
stopped paying attention
because it's just so two-sided and i
want to have the conversations where we
connect with each other as people
and i'm having a lot more of those
conversations rather than like
one side's other side surface
i just yeah totally wow that really
opens it up into some good
thinking because i we're
you know i i feel like we can kind of
sense you know when you when you
interact with someone who
is very caught up in the news cycle
media like who has been watching these
things every day like they
you know they're in facebook groups
about it they're you know and i'm you
know
left right this thing this popular thing
like you're you're
attacking the the blm you're attacking
the the
pedophile ring you're attacking the you
know the antifa
like all these different aspects you
know that our news media and our
um our you know technological connected
culture here gives us
to argue about or talk about or say hey
here's this identity do you belong or do
not belong
and we we're like oh i belong to that
one that's that's that's mine i want to
make sure everybody that i interact with
knows that um we're almost
i i i really keep i keep framing this as
we're talking about this i keep framing
this around
um just like our initial walk up to
someone like you're and like when you
first talk to someone like
because sometimes i feel like nowadays
and i don't remember this from before
maybe i was just
vastly unaware of it there's there's
resentment
like people like we carry
auras of resentment towards people who
are not in the room
and we accidentally project it on to the
person in front of us
and it's so so it is so
when someone goes to meet you if they're
say a far-right person
like like um you know that they
far right and let's say let's say they
they love donald trump they're
huge trump fans um and they approach you
and you know you're wearing i don't know
an andrew yang shirt or you're wearing
wearing even like a rainbow shirt and
they indicate like oh this is a left
person
like they're instantly coming at you
from their avatar of
here's what i i'm the person on the
right i'm talking this person on the
left
so it's almost just like so rather than
rather than hey how are you like what
what's real about you how has your human
experience been so far
you know like we we come from this place
of thinking we know but
we have to approach each other as if we
don't know [__] because that's the truth
we don't know [__] you don't know [__]
about the person across from you
so true i always approach i've
i've recently not so recently but
in the past a handful of years of my
life
i have become so i went through a whole
transition in my life of being
when i was younger i was very annoying
and
i was very self-conscious about being
very annoying
and i'm sure people today would argue
i'm still annoying but i'm okay with it
but when i was younger i was told i was
annoying
so often that i just shut down and
stopped talking
i was like i'm not gonna be annoying i'm
not gonna be myself
i'm just gonna be whatever people think
i should be
and i'll just be quiet and not be told
i'm annoying
and that just
formed my personality in that i
wanted to be whatever anyone wanted me
to be
whereas recently like i said last
handful of years probably
four or six years i'm like realizing
that
i need to come into every situation
exactly as i am because peop
the only people i want around me are
those who love me for exactly as i am
and i don't want to put on any type of
facade i don't want to fit into a
category
i don't want to i don't want to be who
you want me to be
i want you to like me for who i am or we
just won't connect and that's okay
but there was someone who brought it to
my attention or you know like i just
heard it at the right time in my life
they said don't hide from me what
you don't want me to see let me see it
and let me make my own judgment
and i was like that's so true and it was
hard to hear
but just that that statement
like launched me into just being a
hundred percent myself
i'm transparent i'm authentic when i
the job we both have when i interviewed
for it
i normally would be nervous
because i wanted to be exactly who they
wanted me to be
but i went into that interview very calm
and very
like relaxed this is who i am
you know i did my research i know about
the company here's how i think i can be
valuable here's what i know about you
here's what i'm passionate about and i
just went in there like this is me
if you want me then we're going to be
good
if you don't want me then this isn't an
opportunity i want
yeah i oh did you freeze
well and a lot of the
a lot of that the projecting i'm really
working on
um but when we come into a conversation
with another person and we're projecting
it just changes the entire experience
and so i think
understanding ourselves relating to
other people more
when we understand other people we
become able more able to understand
ourselves
and so when we relate to other people
when we come into the conversation
open and without those boundaries and
know what we can be projecting on to
them and realizing it
hopefully in the moment but you know
sometimes we have to analyze those
things afterwards
i just think a lot of i think you're
right a lot of people
especially with politics and just i
don't even know if people can project
with politics like how do you
i don't know maybe you're i think i've
noticed about you
what oh yeah yeah basically saying that
or or
feeling that assuming that they know
what they need to know about the other
person
and assuming they know what they need to
know about themselves even
yeah or experiencing um
feeling that you feel a certain way
and i know you feel the same way but
really you have no idea
that that other person you know like a
lot of
the work that i do is very stressful
people think that i should be very
stressed but
i have learned to manage my stress i
don't feel a lot of this stress
and so you can't put stress on to me you
can't project that onto me you can't say
i'm feeling stress or my job is really
hard
because i don't feel that way and i feel
like that's that's a very small
and very specific example but
when we put each other into these boxes
there's no way to relate to somebody if
you're
already putting them in a box
stereotyping
categorizing pigeonholing like you said
being a left person seeing a right
person you've put each other in these
boxes
and it's once you've put the box
i want to say once you put the wall up
it's
so much harder to break it down than if
you come into the conversation without
the wall in the first place
do you think that we have a lot of
people approaching
approaching each other from behind their
own walls without realizing it like
i think a lot of this is past our
awareness i think a lot of i mean i
i feel like already what what we've been
talking about is um i started
this i started this sense making
sickness series with
my friend spencer and we kind of
basically wanted to solve what the [__]
is going on
like why is everyone losing their mind
why are we acting
insane and why are we acting in childish
and what the hell is going on
so uh like i recorded that episode it's
been a couple months now and spencer and
i still like we text back and forth
every few days
trying to solve these like kind of
concepts or trying to
investigate what's going on i consume a
ton of content i do a lot of writing i
i haven't even gotten to where i feel
comfortable making the second part
and i wanted to make it like a five part
series because it's so complex and
confusing to me
but i think we we're kind of like
pointing right at this area
is there is something going on
now more than ever like over the course
of the last few years let's say 10 years
i guess
our our communication our connection
is weird like it's it's
it's obviously it's advancing because i
mean like look what we're doing right
now like we're
talking in real time you're all the way
across across the same country like
yeah like to where that's three hours
difference in time but we're still
talking at the same you know time here
it's it's so cool but i think that it's
happened so
fast that we're almost just like as
human species
we're confused and we don't know that
we're confused or something
um i i guess
there are certain types i mean like you
and i like we enjoy
philosophical thought like we enjoy um
like complex layers of of thinking to
solve
you know the uh to solve some sort of
problem that's posed
but i think a lot of people
aren't like that at all and they never
stop and think i mean
awareness itself uh this book anthony
demaio awareness
like i read that and um
i mean i was kind of into a lot of that
stuff at that point but he basically
points out he basically talks you
through like
who is the one like what's the point of
you talking right now like where is the
person where's your mind where does it
sit
is it inside your brain are you a little
man inside your head like what's
have you ever thought about these things
before are you aware that like how do
you move your right arm
just all these like kind of surface
level things but we see past the surface
level because we
we meet every we approach situations
with assumptions which is a good thing
and a bad thing
um but
there there seems to be
how do i round this out i think if we
continue to do things the way in which
we have been doing them over the course
of the last four years like whether
we're talking about like the crazy
arguing with social media and politics
and
news and all that i think that's like a
good um
like that's a good thing to point the
camera at but that's just like a symptom
of our underlying underneath here
there's this
weird communication barrier thing where
we don't understand what meaning is we
don't understand what feelings are
we don't understand what the human
condition really is and we can't
certainly
certainly we don't know how to relate it
to the [__]
gdp you know like yeah like the gdp
doing well
what does that have to do with like uh
people i went to school with like
committing suicide and like wanting to
take their own life in in in being like
just not doing mentally well and not
being able to stay on their feet like
these things are very well connected but
the conversation gets like why is it
taboo
it's so strange that it's taboo that
it's weird that it's uncomfortable to
talk about
you know actual human feelings actual
things that are happening
um even you know it's kind of what our
culture does with death we just kind of
avoid talking about it
and if anybody gets anywhere near it
we're like please don't do it please
save them
anything to save them we don't talk
about the value of life the
the lived experience like how are we
making every moment more fulfilling
rather than just trying to extend
the meter of of the length you're alive
it's i i don't know uh
how do like do do you see
does it feel i guess gabriel does it
feel like this to you does it feel like
over the last you know as you've like
grown and changed yourself and just
gotten older and just you know learned
more too
does it feel like that to you does it
feel like we have a weird communication
misinformation barrier
so i want to say i'm glad you said that
it feels like it's taboo for us to talk
about our human emotion because
one of the things that really bugged me
about
business and corporations and things
like that
is that a lot of the old thinking was
that
people are pieces of a machine
and you replace the parts of the machine
that aren't working as fast and as well
as you want them to and
this person or this part of the machine
you know needs to go faster let's get
rid of what's there and
get something that's cheaper and quicker
and does the job better or
just more efficiently rather than seeing
them as people
and i know that there's a whole movement
of
i think they're called b corporations
where they just care more about
the people that work for them and
treating their people correctly
and i haven't looked into them in a long
time but it was a few years ago that i
learned about them
and it was just about treating the
people you work with
and the people who work for you as
actual humans
and i i'm glad you said that it's it
feels like it's taboo to
experience human emotion because a lot
of the time i think the experience
is that you go into a job and you're an
employee and you just work and
then you go home and the job just
doesn't experience you after you go home
and
if you miss a day it's like what the
hell do you want to be fired like you're
not here working
or i'm late why are you late like you
should be here on time there's nothing
else in your life that should
you know like why isn't the machine
working what's what's wrong with this
part of the machine you need to do
better you know and it's like you could
have a whole family emergency
i just that old way of thinking
i think there wasn't enough
understanding there wasn't enough
compassion there wasn't enough empathy
and that's the way i am is i always try
to
have the human emotion side of it
whenever i work with people i see you as
a human
and if you're late on a project like
what's going on
and you know people don't deliver on
deadlines i have a family emergency
i can't just be like okay deal with your
family emergency you had a deadline
like i'm sick i can't work
i and you know like need to push the
deadline like
i understand you're laying in bed like
with a flu
you're not going to be able to even if
it's you know all this working from home
stuff it's hard when you're
feeling dead coughing just want to go to
sleep have a headache and your eyes
closed like
wanting to get on your computer i
i just wish there were more
of that everywhere just more of
understanding people more understanding
of like
you woke up today were you hungry could
that have affected
the way you interacted with people until
you ate breakfast
you know like did you snap at someone
and you didn't have enough water
like what could be humanly going on with
you
that made you react in this way so
a lot of these people who are very you
know
um all i can say is like friction
people that have a lot of friction or
come into conversations very
um closed-minded like
what's how's your diet like do you
exercise like
how often do you think about your
actions do are you conscious
of what the way you're saying what
you're saying can affect the other
person do you think about it
and if you're not the type of person who
thinks about about those types of things
what kind of person am i speaking to you
know like
what are you aware of in your own world
and how can i
change my how can i like rotate my lens
about you as a person in our
conversation to see
like where you're coming from yeah i
really like where you're taking this
because
i feel like the whole time i i've been
thinking
gosh why doesn't this person practice
their awareness like why don't they
see that they're feeling these emotions
rather than where you just took it
and i think that's important is how
could i better understand where he
actually is
like i guess trying to understand where
he is
so i can try to get him to think more
like me isn't really
like super helpful and that's another
way to get this other person
who is you know someone who's um just
stuck to that friction like you said
that's a good way to get them to shut
down i mean nobody nobody wants to
like if i approach someone and they're
like you're coming at me all wrong you
need to restart
i'd be like what you know what
so so how do we so okay
instead of allowing me to be thinking
gosh see that's the conundrum though is
because so many so many times i'll think
about this stuff and i'm like dude
these [__] they just need
awareness they need awareness of their
own
because me if i'm having a conversation
or um you know even if i'm just like you
know
tyler and i are having a beer after a
show and we're both
you know just getting kind of fired up
i'll notice like
if if i'm okay i'll apologize even oh
geez sorry
hey i was getting fired up i'm really
passionate about that subject you know
i'll notice the state that i'm in as i'm
in it
and if it's going too far if it's
tipping the canoe a little too far if we
get a little bit of water in the boat
i'm going to be like okay but you know
this is i love you
i appreciate your conversation brother
like thank you for listening to me i
don't mean any harm
let's let off the throttle a little bit
so now you can say what you need to say
and that's how a conversation works
conversations can be passionate
conversations can be heated
conversations can be
um you know fueled fueled by
real inner emotions but they can't have
like a whole fog a whole like
like protect protective screen over them
to where you don't even get to those
underlying emotions where it's just i
don't know what you're talking about
absolutely i definitely feel that i was
gonna say that that the conversations
definitely depend on those emotions but
we're not even getting there because
we're
so in this i like what you said fog or
um
like those uh those walls that fog up
you know we're behind like plexiglas
that just fogged and
you know like we can see the other
person like we can see that they're
there
but we don't like understand that
they're a person like us like we can
just kind of see
their form and it's like oh that's
definitely a person
but we don't under we can't understand
them we can't connect with them because
there's just like this
foggy glass between us and
i don't the connection comes from
those emotions and that passion that
you're talking about
and i don't know there are just some
people who
i don't know if they're not aware or
if they just don't think about things
or they're just their mind is just
closed or they haven't
i i think i was i was exploring
something recently and
i don't remember specifically what it
was but i wanted to i kind of wanted to
test it on my family to see what they
thought about it
and i so my thinking was
like something i don't even remember it
but it was something to the effect of
like
there can be multiple ways to think
about this
and i realize like there can be multiple
ways to view this or thinking
think about this or multiple outcomes
from this thing and i went to my family
and they actually said whatever i was
thinking of in the topic i was talking
about
they were just like straight minded
there's
only this way no one can be any
different and i was like
when you say that are you sure like what
if someone else
you know thinks a little bit differently
maybe maybe they don't agree that the
answer is no maybe they
they think the answer can be yes
sometimes and they were all just like
no and it just
it go so so what so what that exact
moment
where they they're just like no what are
you talking like where they reject
to me to me that's a truth like what you
point out like ah
don't don't forget about other existing
perspectives because there's almost
eight billion people in the world
and they say no like what what what is
that moment like what's happening within
them
and is that is that wrong or are is
there a different way we can approach it
or
do do they feel maybe they feel as if
they're being attacked
as if we're saying you're wrong and we
just don't like being wrong so much that
we're like
i'm gonna back i'm gonna double down on
my [__] is that
yeah i don't i don't know and it's it
was it
kind of it was funny to me number one
because it was something i had already
been like building and thinking about
and they just brought it up without
even me initiating something but it just
showed me that people who i relate to
and understand
and really like they're literally my my
family like my parents and my brother
my relatives we're blood related
some of the most intelligent people i
know are not
thinking about this i i don't even
remember what it was but
they aren't even considering that other
people can
think other things or feel differently
about this topic
and they were just like no
and i i brought up all the things i had
been thinking about you know
what if someone has this experience
maybe they could say yes what if this
person you know maybe they would feel
yes or yes sometimes or yes you know at
some point or
in some capacity and they were just like
that's dumb
no and i don't even know if it was
i don't even know if it was something
defensive that they would
you know try and they feel in themselves
and would try to defend or
get offended by but it just seemed like
they hadn't
considered there could be a yes
okay so sometimes this level of
conversation is
is intimidating
and taxing on people so like sure
so maybe maybe kind of what's going on
is
you are approaching as just an
inquisitive philosophical thought
thinker a thought figure and in
and that's just how you enjoy
interacting
um but but if other people don't it
almost
feels like a challenge like so you're
just saying like wait don't you want to
explore like
let's let's see if we can get closer to
truth together you know like what
because because i mean if you're
anything like me it's basically like it
when someone else opens up
and they allow me to like you know climb
inside their brain for a second
and they climb inside mine and we're
trying to solve this thing because i for
me i'm
i'm thinking in real time i'm thinking
out loud i'm letting it like fall out
because i think that's so fun i think
that's like the one of the more
beautiful things of life we don't know
what we're going to think next we don't
know what we're thinking about we don't
know what we're going to say next
we i think it's so fun to
recognize like right now it's like you
know you know it's not right on the
surface but deep down layers down
there's this thing where abrial you and
i both we've been here for less than 30
years of peace
and we don't really know the truth about
the universe we're both trying to figure
it out so like
why don't we try to figure it out
together like oh maybe it means this
maybe it means this so
when but you can't just approach
everybody
with that level of inquisitory nature
because
because because i guess i guess i'll ask
you what happens there
when you do come at someone who's not
trying to inquire
on their belief systems at all times
what happens within them when you come
at them
with this hey let's challenge a belief
system i can tell you from personal
experience they just get annoyed
like i'm asking um
like why would you think about it like
what does it matter
like why why does it matter what you
said it's in the past like why would you
analyze it or why would you
why would you be thinking about all
these philosophical things like does it
does it affect you does it matter is it
gonna change your experience they don't
even get that far they're just like
why am i gonna spend my time thinking
like that and i don't
it's a hard it's a hard you know thing
to explain like
i don't know don't you want to see where
your mind goes with these things
and it's i think that's just a
difference in personality it's a
difference in culture it's a difference
in
you know it's just a difference in
people some people want to have these
deep
philosophical conversations and we can
go for hours about it and then
some people just think it's a waste of
time why would you go
i got a lot of stuff to do like why
would i sit here and think about these
things
right yeah because okay so
have you ever had have you ever had um
and feel free to say no if you don't
want to talk about on a podcast have you
ever had like any um
uh not necessarily like psychedelic
experiences but any like mind altering
where your
your consciousness is different like
even through through like extensive
breath work or lots of yoga where you
can kind of get into like
let's just say altered states of
consciousness um i mean
like you've you've been drunk before you
know yeah
i i i wouldn't say i've been in anything
like drastically different
um but i've been in situations that have
completely changed the way i feel about
things
and the way i act and things like that
but okay i've been pretty sober
yeah that's that that's pretty similar i
mean because i've gotten to different
you know levels of mind where
my i'll have it's almost it's not so
much about the experience like i'll have
an
experience you know so if this is not
what i'm talking about but but if
someone has say
say they take psychedelics and they have
a mystical experience then their life
has changed forever
but the thing that happens is their
perception of
who they are what they're doing what
they should do with their life
what it means to be alive what's the
meaning of light like all these things
can be shifted and that changes your
perception which in turn changes
um your the interactions that you have
and how you have them
after so i i've had
you know just within the last you know
maybe three years or so
i've had a few experiences like this
like where and i've talked about this
which is totally weird but
you know i had a lot of trauma healing
and um you know a lot of just doing a
lot of yoga and breath work and cannabis
and all this stuff
um in it it changed my perception of
what i thought
and then also a lot of just philosophy
like you can listen to a lot of
philosophers
you know you take a few days and listen
to the same philosophy like if you
listen to just nothing but terrence
mckenna or
alan watts or ramadas or something for a
few days and like have no interaction
with people
your perception about the world around
you will certainly change
and that's that fascinates me as someone
who is very interested in philosophy and
psychology
i like oh my god it fills me up i love
to do it it seriously excites me
but those those changes in perception
i think to other people when they're
approached or when people see them
coming they're almost so scary because
a lot of people in our culture and this
is not a bad thing i'm just saying this
is like a product of our you know
late stage capitalism culture we have
here we're trying to constantly define
ourselves so we can stick to that
identity
and then we're trying to approach our
situations
with the assurance of the other person
knowing our identity
and i think that
hmm i i think that
i i guess i i'm trying to find a bridge
over to identity
because i think what i'm trying to say
is that our identity often
blocks us from realizing
true inner feelings that like as a human
they're they're gifts but we kind of
have blocked ourselves from feeling
what's real inside of us
and we instantly go back to like what
would my avatar do what would my avatar
say
yeah i i think that
it's interesting because our identity
blocks us
from our experiencing our feelings is
what you said
um yeah our our identity blocks us from
really like experiencing who we are
the identity like that the identity wall
that we want to put up
being stuck to our identity that's the
identity that's not fluid because the
reality of our identity is it's fluid
it's just like water it's changing at
all times but we
we can't conceptualize that yeah i
and i think we can't actually
our true identity like you're saying
flows
but i don't think we can understand that
without
we can't understand ourselves
i think without understanding other
people and then bringing it back to
ourselves
feeling how that feels understanding
ourselves a little bit more
bringing ourselves out to others seeing
how it
you know turns up with them coming back
and like you know just this constant
like
back and forth and realizing like
a lot of me trying to not be annoying is
you know i would like try something out
and i would say something
at some volume level i used to be very
loud i'm still very loud but
and i and it's funny being around my
family they're all yelling
and i'm like why are we all yelling like
can't we just be a little bit calmer
and they're like what are you talking
about like you made us go to this level
because you
used to yell yourself exactly so it's
just everyone in my family is very loud
and i always used to be very loud so i
would approach situations where
i was very loud and very you know like
up and outspoken and just all over the
place and people would tell me i'm
annoying and weird and so i would just
come back and like see how that feels
yeah i would hold it
and you know a lot and
but but you learn from that and so
instead of just being like
all in your face and being loud and just
talking fast and all these
my dad always tells me to slow down and
so
i come out a little bit and i see how it
works out
and i come back and i'm like okay how
did we feel about that
they didn't say i was annoying did i
care if what they thought about me and
that experience like
how did i feel about that in the
experience you know i feel like i was
being annoying i felt like
you know i saw their face maybe they
didn't like it when i reached this level
that kind of thing and then like you see
how you can interact with certain people
you see that
certain people want you to be quiet
certain people want you to be louder
and you can kind of see how you can just
like maneuver yourself
but in all of that maneuvering like
where is your base
and i've realized my base is this
calm light happy
optimistic realist that i bring
the best into situations and if people
are feeding up to the higher levels and
stuff maybe i can get louder and i can
get a little bit faster and
we can go back and forth and do all this
stuff but if the situation is
i can be more towards my base then we
can have a slow conversation
we can you know be at this level and
those kinds of things so
i feel like people need in order for
people to be more understanding of
everyone else in cliche they need to
start with themselves
we need to understand ourselves more but
i don't
it's it's really hard and it takes a
long time and
i've been working on myself a lot and
one of the things i've always believed i
think i
i was thinking about this in like 10th
grade
so what's that like 2 4
8 10 or 12 years ago
my biggest thing is i don't do new
year's resolutions i
do new changes every day
every day something about me should be
different and i'm just change
my new year's resolutions by the end of
the year by the next year
i should be exponentially different
because i'm changing every single day
and yeah and so this idea
like i'll wait until next week i'll wait
until i'll wait until next month i'll
wait until tomorrow
i don't believe in that because god
forbid a meteor strikes and like you
know or
the person you're thinking of wanting to
be different with gets in a car accident
or
you like i just smashed my face into the
door the other day and like i couldn't
open my eyes and like my first thought
was like i'm so disoriented oh my god
what if i'm blind
and like those
those things can happen just so like you
could fall
and like hit the corner of a table and
knock one of your eyes out and
you know never never have depth
perception again
and just those kinds of things
are so real some people think i'm
pessimistic for
thinking that way but i just it's a
presence
you get a presence from thinking that
way
thinking that any interaction you have
with someone
could be your last one like
somebody leaves in the heat of the
moment
that could be the last thing you guys
ever say to each other
if you like you never know
and so i'm a huge it's a big deal to me
the interaction and that's why i'm so
conscious of
being in the moment and that's one of
the biggest things i've always worked on
is because
when i was in college i got straight a's
which means i studied my ass off
i got straight a's but i didn't have a
lot of life experience you know i did a
lot of like
studying and people went out to football
games and i was reading
my boring ass history book like i did a
lot of that
and so a lot of my time was
i'm rushing from one place to another
while
reading and thinking and listening to
something
on my way to going somewhere and
i was never present and then when i
started working i started working while
i was in school so i did school
full-time and then i worked as full-time
as possible
and i was just going from so much and i
would get to like
i think i talked to you about this last
time actually i would get into a
situation and be like
yeah like this is great i just gotta go
do this next thing and like i'd always
be like
on the ready to go do the next thing
and i would never just like be
here so that's one of the things that i
really have been working on
and i think that is important
and not enough people in my experience
understand what being here means
right i mean i like it's something that
definitely because i dealt with a lot of
um disassociation when i was younger
um it's like a it's like a trauma
response basically you know like
the pain of the moment is so severe that
your mind
protects you from it by floating the
[__] away
uh yeah so it was pretty profound for me
too
like the uh i mean it was like three
years ago when i started meditating and
doing yoga and stuff
learning about the present moment um and
what that really means like it was
it's it's so weird to me that that's so
profound like it was so
changing like life altering changing to
me to discover like
oh wow like you're thinking at all times
you're thinking like we're
i mean we have 60 000 thoughts a day or
something like that that's crazy we
don't think we are we're
we're just a ball of thoughts and habits
walking around but we think we're
completely in control
we're like yeah i'm choosing what to
think next whatever um
like the you know
that's kind of like a lot of my
philosophy
in in life as as it's still unfolding
you know i'm still trying to figure out
like really what is something that what
what's a what's a value
and and uh um you know things that like
i think will stick with me throughout my
whole life like this is just who i am
this is who i'm going to always be
because i'm a very changing fluid person
i love changing i love evolving i love
the same thing like you were talking
about um but
a lot of my philosophy lately is with
all self-actualization is basically
how do i in each moment that i am given
how do i enjoy it to its to its fullest
because i'm aware that we're not going
to arrive anywhere
like i'm not like how can i work my ass
off now
so i can retire and have 50 margaritas a
day
until i pass out and drown in the pool
you know like i want to
th the life that you live like we don't
go
we don't take any of this with us we the
the things that we think we are you know
the ego mind like our identity our
identification with our name and who we
are
it's just it doesn't go into black
nothingness of suffering when we're gone
it's just gone
we don't experience we're not the
conscious experiencer of it so while you
do have this
experience while you do have this life
how could i
absorb it more fully how could i be more
here
in each moment because like you said
what if i suddenly
like i i'm not really there and i'm
i'm at dinner with my friend and and
we're you know having a beer or whatever
but i'm really distracted i'm on my
phone
and i'm like yeah okay cool cool frank
yeah whatever like
see you later and then he gets in a car
wreck on the way home like i'd be like
wow yeah
i sure wish that i that i would have
been more present with him and it's not
about like you know
finding places that you regret trying to
stamp out regret before it happens but
i think so i had a friend actually
gabrielle who um
when we were in high school uh
phenomenal skateboarder cool dude one of
my good buddies
he was cleaning his room get this he was
cleaning his room and he had
arms an arm load of stuff um like and he
was trying to open the door like
finishing up cleaning his room i think
and in in his arm was a handheld
uh i think handheld pellet gun that
happened to be loaded
happened to not have the safety on in
opening his doorknob it fell hit his
knee shot his own eye out
yeah literally happened when we were
kids like i mean just so
you never you never would have thought
you know in in watching like the
the beauty of that human man just like
watching him re-learn how to skateboard
like re-learn how to like do all these
things and experience this like tragic
loss of
you know losing like all the vision in
one eye and having a replacement eye and
stuff
that could happen at any moment like at
any moment we could be trying to open
the damn door with too much [__] in our
hands and shoot our eye out
so what it's it's not about trying to
avoid those moments it's not about never
being uncomfortable
it's not about listening to our fear in
in staying in our safe caves so nothing
bad ever happens and we can plan
everything and control everything
it's about while you're being courageous
while you're living life while you're um
you know looking for different sometimes
difficult sometimes easy sometimes
fun sometimes not as fun experiences
it's basically how do you
be more present with it how do you
really be there how do you really
breathe in each moment to its fullest to
me that's what it's all about
and i'll tell you there was
um because of the way our job works and
there's so there's a
a real season and then you're off
um when i first started
i completely disappeared mentally
during our show season and then i was
able to like
recover and i mean i was also younger
and not as aware of myself as i am now
i would say i've always been aware of
myself but i'm you know we're just
always growing
so when i first started and i've been
doing this job for four years now
when i first started it was like i
disappeared i wasn't mentally like
my life was work i would stay up all
night and work
any work that needed to be done got done
i would just keep working i'm available
24 7.
you call my phone i answer it and i get
on whatever i needed to get on to do
i would skip eating i would skip
exercising i would skip all this stuff
because i don't have time because i have
to work and
what i've fallen into or what i didn't
fall into it was intentional
what i've changed is that
i need my own base
and i add work into it so
i haven't missed a workout i haven't
missed a meal i'm i've
shopped specifically for my busy
schedule
you know like i buy pre-chopped
vegetables i buy easy to make meals i do
those things that are make my life
easier
but i don't work
all day i do my other things and i add
work in
and i don't disappear i don't
you know like i realize i'm a human and
sometimes when i'm working so much and
staring at a screen and just sitting
there for hours that i
lose track of time and forget that i
need to breathe and take a break
and drink a glass of water and just like
decompress for a second
and i think you were talking about the
vagus nerve and just
getting out of the stress space
and just grounding yourself and
realizing like
i'm here on earth and there are like
bugs and leaves and
nature and planes flying in the air and
all these kinds of things going on that
like what's in my laptop and in my phone
are so like such a small percentage of
my experience as a human
and i it's taken me a long time to
realize that
and i still i'm a hard worker and i
still want to say like
i don't want to identify with being a
workaholic i
i think i i'm a little bit of a
workaholic but like
i also want to take time for myself and
i want to
i want to i want to work a lot during
the weekdays so that the people who have
actual schedules when they're relaxing
on the weekend
i want to be able to relax with them
like i i want to be present i don't
wanna
disappear during the busy times i don't
you know like we have a lot of shows in
march i don't wanna
disappear in march and just watch march
go by
that's one of the things we always talk
about is we forget what happens in our
show
season and we we forget and it just
buzzes by and then suddenly it's
june and we're like what happened and
then we go into it next year and we're
like
well what did we do last time and we're
like i don't even remember
we just disappear i don't
i'm not doing it anymore okay i feel
like
like what we're kind of talking about
i'm not trying to oversimplify but it
just seems like gratitude honestly
like gratitude really just like like
remembering to
you know even though work can get
exhausting even though it can get tiring
like there is things that you love about
it there's definitely things you love
about it it is
there is a point where it's like i've
been working a lot i've been
building up to this thing and like
especially for shows for us it's like
weeks and weeks of work like for you
especially as like the facilitator of
the middle person of all these things
and then also doing all the graphics and
organizing everything yeah everybody and
planning all the flights and all this
stuff
like that's so stressful and sometimes
it is so fast-paced there's so many
moving parts that you don't
always get to slow down and be like hey
i know i'm
i'm booking your flight and we're
waiting for a response but we should we
should really remember to value this
moment you know you can't always bring
the present moment into just cut through
everything and be like hey remember the
present moment
but i think that there is times where
you do have to insert it so for us the
live events
there is a moment where it's almost you
want to take off your headphones and
just
like
this looks good you know we we we did
this like
wow like i'm proud of myself like this
is this is an experience like
on my deathbed if there's some sort of
like memory flashback boom boom boom
what am i proud of like i hope you know
maybe this is one of them hope it is
because
i'm proud of this and this is good like
wow like this is good what does it smell
like what does it feel like you know
what clothes am i wearing just
really being present with that moment so
i think that
do you think that not being present
takes away our ability
or our connection as a human species to
feel gratitude
i i would say
yes not being present
keeps us from feeling gratitude which
stops us from connecting with other
people
and it's i think it's a it's a different
type of
person someone who is grateful
for a lot in life
it you i think gratitude comes from a
lot of pain
and i think compassion and understanding
comes from a lot of pain
and it's hard to expect a lot of people
to be grateful and compassionate when
they haven't experienced that type of
pain
and so like people who have their
parents have died
and their friends have died
and they themselves have gone through
their own ego death
or experienced just a lot of like a
really
hard point in their lives when
you have gone through that you can
relate to someone who has gone through
something painful as well and so
something that we've talked about before
and
i was talking to my trainer about is i
talked to you last time about i was
going to the gym and i just didn't feel
like i was good at working out it didn't
feel like my body looked good i didn't
feel like all these things
and she reminded me abrielle you're
forgetting your gratitude
like thank goodness you're able to work
out
you're so privileged you're able to go
to the gym afford a gym membership
you're so healthy you are so lucky to
have grown up in a family that was
financially stable enough that they
could afford healthy foods
i learned proper balanced nutrition i
didn't eat
fast food until i was in high school and
i bought it myself
my parents never they raised me on like
dinner is five ounces of protein
two blocks of vegetables and like a
different kind of carb like soup or rice
or something like that
and so like whenever i look at a meal i
know
where the balance is and how big it is
in comparison like
maybe you're having this much meat and
you're having this much vegetables but
like they compare
to each other so thank goodness i'm able
to just know that thank goodness i'm so
healthy
i woke up this morning i can breathe i
got in my car and it started
i i got to the gym and there are people
there and i'm surrounded by people who
care
about their fitness and their well-being
and their health and we live in a world
where that's starting to become
like a normal thing people caring about
their health like thank goodness
this is my experience and that's just
that she lost her mom a year and a half
ago
those that type of thinking only comes
from
extreme pain this type of gratitude like
i wake up and i look at my ceiling i
have a window right by my bed
so every morning when i wake up it's
just bright i don't have blackout
curtains i don't like those i like
waking up too
bright like and i wake up
i'm in this bed that i paid for in an
apartment that i can afford because i
have a job that i love
that pays me enough money to live here
and i'm awake i'm breathing
my body's a little sore and that's great
because it's from a workout that i put
work into
it's just growing as well like you're
yeah
yeah and it's just thank goodness
this is my experience i wake up i wake
up to my cats yelling at me
thank goodness i'm able to like afford
two animals that support me
and my happiness and i can pet them all
the time and right
you know yeah like i mean because you
know as much as it annoys you
if they wake you up and they're just
meowing or something and you're like
really
i mean when you know there's gonna be
come there's gonna come in time when
when the
the cats are gonna move on you know when
in their life cycle
so true so you're gonna be like dang it
i you know there's gonna be time in your
life where you're like i wish i could
hear
them waking my ass up in the morning you
know i just don't know
i realized i forgot it was my cat's
birthday recently she's turning five she
turned five
i have had this cat since she was since
her umbilical cord was attached
like i have had this cats i raised her
and she is five years old i'm like
in shock they tell you that about
children that they just like grow up and
you have to like watch them
but i'm just like looking at her like oh
my god
you've existed for five years it's so
crazy
yeah it's so nuts and you know just
i i have to take time to play with my
pets and that takes time
away from work and i have to take time
to
take care of them clean their litter box
buy them food and
make food for myself and all of these
things in life take
time away from work and i've always been
comparing
how much time things take away from work
meanwhile work takes time away from my
life experience
yeah you get caught up in every second
i'm not working is another dollar i'm
not making you know or whatever it is i
i
i i have with with my dog blue
um that's something that i actually had
to like he helped me again
just learn more presents um i i would
have times i'm some i'm
constantly listening to stuff like
youtube i'm just constantly absorbing i
think you're like this a lot too
um just like listening to podcasts or
youtube or some background something
um but i started like kind of
intentionally
you know come home from work and i'm
listening to something because usually
i'll get home
put in headphones just listen to
something or continue listening to what
i was listening to in the car
um like stretch out in the garage and do
my little like routine
come upstairs and if he's in if he's in
here if he's staying over
then what i would try to do is take out
my headphones and put my phone away and
just
just cuddle the guy for 10 15 minutes
like just be with him
just let him nuzzle me just you know
talk with him just hang out with him
just exist with him
and and i really i really came to like
like that that moment of an intentional
presence where i'm like
i could be listening to this thing and
then also just kind of petting my dog
that sounds cool too but no man i love
this dog and i really want to like
feel that to its fullest degree so i'm
gonna i'm gonna take out the headphones
and i'm gonna get present with them
and then that that builds up uh that
that builds up gratitude like
by being present you build up gratitude
because then i would have times where
i'm driving home from work and i'm just
thinking like oh i get to pet my dog
like
you know it just excites me so um dude
what you said about compassion like
compassion is is compassion is learned
through pain or something you said
holy [__] like that's powerful i was i
was thinking you know
when you first started that i was just
like wow like you're reaching into
something inside me for sure
because i you know i think a lot of my
um my you know
emotional intelligence but um
also you know sensitivity but also uh
i don't know i think my empathy for
humanity and my compassion for others is
is because of me experiencing you know
i'm a hurt people
you know i experienced pain when i was
younger
and then like now my life is like i'm
not gonna like
bring that that pain on to on to other
people or i want to like
learn how to work with that or i want to
learn how to make other people not feel
the pain that i experienced and
yeah so that that does build compassion
i'm almost like looking for like
you know how can i help you how can i
help you not feel the the
the terrible things that i have felt
inevitably as a human being myself
so yeah compassion brings pain that was
that's [__] powerful
it absolutely is like how can i make
sure that you don't feel these feelings
anytime i in
work in just
like when people are going through
anything
people are you know i have a friend
who's now a new mom and they're new
parents and
um people i ask to do things for work
and people who are going through
breakups and people who are going
through you know whatever it is just
like
i have felt so low
and i have felt so stressed
that maybe i don't know how you feel
but i can certainly empathize and
i want to do whatever i can do to help
you get out of that
because i have been there and all i
wanted was someone to just
like reach a hand you know what i mean
and that like the the new mom
anything i can do to help her i just
wanted because
having a baby is freaking crazy i don't
i've never had a baby obviously but just
like
it's a whole life shift and you're now
responsible for this little person and
every single thing you do
has to be for this little person and
is seen by this little person even as
babies
every single thing you do the
pace at which you get off the couch
the amount that you sleep the
level the volume level of your voice
when you
speak to anybody the energy you bring
into any conversation
from birth until death affects
that little baby just so like
anything i can do to help this person i
want to
any and with work oh my god i was just
talking about this the other day
um talking about how i manage my stress
and
things like that and i was talking about
um
last year when we went from all live
events to all virtual events
there was this crunch where i was the
only one working
actually i was the only one working with
you and we were the only people putting
these virtual shows together
and it was just so much work in
like 13 days i think was a span we did
10 shows in 13 days
something like that and we had to like
learn different ways and new ways to do
it i
like i i thought that i had it down at
the beginning but i was like wait i have
to do this
all [__] different i have to do this
it's so different i was like
show on my mobile phone while trying to
live record and like time everything
perfectly as if it was a live show i was
just totally
and it was the expectation was put on
you that you would do it like we
normally would
when you learned that there was actually
a difference in how you should be doing
it it didn't work i had to do it a
different way
exactly and so when we went through that
experience
i did not sleep there was a a span
there there was a span where we had so
many shows in like a five-day period
that i worked 95 hours
in like four or five days i got
no sleep i was sitting down
on my laptop from 9 00 am until 11 pm
and then i got tired
so i stood up and worked from 11 p.m to
like
8 a.m and then so i so i went to sleep
and i woke back up but no you're like i
stood up
and did another time i literally like i
have a bar
in my kitchen and i i stood up at the
bar working
from 11 p.m until 8am and then i would
like make breakfast take a shower get
back on my computer sit down
9am to 11pm stand up and just be working
i wasn't eating i wasn't sleeping it was
so stressful mentally
physically like my body hurt from
standing
all night and not eating and not
sleeping
and like i would render something and i
had seven minutes for it to render and i
couldn't do anything else and so i would
just like
sleep real quick and then like when it
went yeah
and it was so taxing
i don't feel any stress anymore like it
was
so traumatizing for me that there's
nothing i experience anymore that is
even slightly stressful to me i
you know like there are a lot of things
on my plate right now for sure
but i don't feel any type of stress
about them because
nothing compared to what i went through
right yeah so you you grow
through the you know i mean you grow
through adversity like some say but you
know
growing through just hardship basically
and so like
now i have a different understanding
of stress and when other people are
stressed like i know how you feel how
can i help you
there players because i i was just
there like i was so so when you're
stressed though
so that that's an important thing that
you do you bring compassion to it and
you
and you don't because what i'll see
some people do when they're like
like oh i you know i i've worked i'm on
i'm working my 16 hour days and then
someone comes in they're like oh dude
i'm so tired like i just worked 12 hours
like
and immediately what the 16 hour person
could do is like bro
that ain't [__] i worked 16 hours and i
haven't slept
and you know my mom's in the hospital in
my you know and they're just like here's
how
what you have to say and what you're
going through is not valid because
mine's more valid than you
instead of doing that you're like i feel
you
like i oh man it was pretty rough when i
was on my 12 hours like what can i do
you need water
do you need like a lemonade you know
like what all of
your experience is your experience
the worst thing that's happening to you
is the worst thing that's happening to
you
i don't i don't like when people say
like you know
oh you think you're hungry but there are
children starving in africa
like there's not much that i can compare
myself to people starving in africa but
it doesn't affect that like
this is the worst thing that's ever
happened to me you know
there's not it just it doesn't matter it
doesn't really work
i don't think that stuff works comparing
yourself to
yeah i'm hungry people are starving in
africa but like this is the most hungry
i've ever been or
yes my job is hard but there are people
who are working harder like it doesn't
comparing myself to that someone else's
situation just doesn't work and so
i never want to put on someone like
i do a lot in my job like i do a lot
and you only have one role like
you're only the audio director like can
you really be stressed you know
like i'm never gonna be like that it's
just
if there's something that you're
experiencing and it's very stressful for
you
then it's very stressful for you and i
respect and understand that
and like how can i help okay i i have
i'm not trying to steamroll but i'm
gonna take this
i want to connect this part right here
back to what we started with with
basically like
not you know at the beginning we're
talking about trying to talk to someone
who's let's say like a super um
you know mega person or a very war very
you know they're very hardcore
into their into their beliefs you
you bring
bringing compassion and understanding in
their
lived experience because because exactly
how we
are like i i get you i get you i totally
get where you're coming from it's hard
for us to bring that
same level of understanding and
compassion into
like you know like say we're talking
someone who's like very obsessed with
with q and on quainon or whatever
and they've been spending 16 hours a day
on these like forums and like there i
mean
you know their their entire belief
system is basically like this is the
most true
information i've ever read because you
can learn you can
dive into the into a lot of that stuff
and if you're learning about it for
weeks and weeks and months and months or
years even like it's it's your truth and
so
reality for sure so so how do we
that's where like there there's this
part with with
you know kind of you know empathic or or
um compassionate people or just people
who like we want to understand we want
to be like oh
like you're going through pain or oh
you're going through trouble or oh like
you're you feel like you're being lied
to by
by corporations by the government like
you feel like you're being lied to it in
um and you know
people are disobeying you and you don't
have any trust like
how do we in these moments where we're
having these weird
especially in america just right now
politics is an easy lens but there's so
many expanding out like there's so many
different little levels of this
how do we bring that much compassion
because we haven't experienced that
ourselves so we haven't gone
like 10 layers deep on like these crazy
conspiracy theories or whatever it is
it's not a conspiracy theory it's hard
for us to to bring that compassion
because we're like oh my god like
you believe something very drastically
different than me i don't even know
where to start i don't even know how to
treat you it doesn't seem like you're
even willing to listen to me even if i
am kind of offering space
i don't know i i i i can't exactly
propose a
specific question here but does this
does this make sense to you i was just
trying to
grip this line back to solving that that
problem of misconduction
i know what you're saying and i i think
it comes from
or i think it not it can be solved by
but it can be helped by just trying to
understand people
like where they come from like why are
you
so what makes what allows you to become
so obsessed with something
and i'll tell you one of the
so just um separate example um
something that i really went through in
my relationship
learning the craziest thing to me about
my boyfriend
is that i've never met someone like him
and i just could not understand him
i could not for the first like i want to
say
10 months to a year of our relationship
i
was just trying to like figure this
person out
i could not understand who or
why like why do you think this way
and you know he's he's a very stubborn
person
and he's very hard-headed wants to be
right
wants to be like the leader wants to be
the um he likes he's very independent
and he all these kinds of things and i'm
just like what makes you such a
hard like top like alpha
man alpha yeah alpha type person like
what is that
and it took me forever to just like
understand
the dynamics of being an only child
because i'm not an only child
and so much of his personality i think
comes from being an only child an only
child you learn
so much independence you're depended on
to
be like good to your parents because
like you're the only offspring you're
the only thing they have to
really nurture so there comes
a lot of i think a lot of his
personalities based off of
being an only child and so many things
come from that and i i see so many
things about him that i'm like
that's a tendency because you didn't
have any siblings you were never
like things he doesn't think about maybe
because he
he never depends on anyone else and i'm
like you know i want to go to things and
support you i want
like why aren't you asking me about
these things why don't you do this my
expectations
why don't you do this why don't you do
that because he's never had anyone
to do those things with i've always had
a brother for him though
is it like mind-blowing is he like
really like you're no
grateful or he just doesn't care so he's
just he's just like i don't i've never
needed it
and i'm just like yeah i'm like why
isn't it mind-blowing to you that like
someone cares about you and he's like
i've never needed it it's never been
something that it's never an expectation
and it's just like
it's mind-blowing to me that you know
someone can be that way
but it's just it's what you learn and so
bringing that back to what you asked i
think we can learn a lot about people
like
people who don't trust the government
did they grow up with their parents
together
like are there have their are their
parents separated or not because
separated parents can make you um
not believe in people or have you been
cheated on like that can
that can really affect your trust issues
have you yourself
done something that can um make you not
trust
other people because you know you can't
trust yourself how much do you trust
yourself are you projecting this lack of
trust on
other people and i'm using that example
because
that's a personal experience so um but
like i think
once we if we run into this person
that's just like
so hard about i have these political
views i believe in this conspiracy
theory
i believe in this i believe in that like
what makes you
such a sh close-minded sure about this
type of person like do you have
siblings that loved you did your
parents hug you like all these types of
things and
you can't ask someone you know like
they're upset about
biden winning you can't just be like
does your mother ever hug you when you
were little
so tell me about your childhood trauma
since you voted for this mother but you
know
exactly but like that's what i want to
that's that's that's what i want to
understand like what do you do for work
okay cool that's that's like your role
and your responsibilities
what do you do like when you go home
everyone's working for home or like when
you go to work like
do you sit down on your desk and you
love every second of working or are you
stressed all the time
and what is being stressed all the time
how does that affect like
when you go home and you're with your
family do you see your family when
you're home
are you single are you upset that you're
single do you love that you're single do
you have children do you have a dog
do you hate animals like what type of
person
are you and what makes you feel that way
and
i just think there are a lot of people
who don't think like that who don't like
understand that way or want to analyze
that way well i mean we
we it's just like we're talking about
we're always trying to
we're always trying to when it comes to
our identities with like uh
you know um again throwing the word ego
in there i know it's overused but
a lot of our identities we're trying to
take snapshots at all times we're trying
to be like this is me this is who i am
like this is here's who i am and but we
we you know again there's a
the actuality of reality is
we're fluid we're always changing but it
and so that means that who you are right
now
at this very second has everything to do
with
how you were treated when you were
younger like you know all the the time
is only right now but
you you're acting out this long
drawn-out 30-year process
of exactly what's been happening to you
since you were younger like you
are you know like uh
like dr joe dispenza says a a
a mood or an emotion becomes a mood
a mood becomes a personality like when
you when you just hold on to it you know
so
like it's your personality today because
you got into a mood
you know like some like too many series
of arguments with your parents when
you're younger
or whatever and or even me i can tell
um and it's not with resentment that i
hold this but just in retrospect
and as i'm doing all this healing and
trying to like really dissect who i am
and
like okay like i'm an artistic like i'm
not
artistic you know contemplative think
like i i enjoy
thinking in ethereal ways
i enjoy a lot of my art artistic sides
are
kind of born through my trauma like my
like through my younger years of things
that i experienced that were bad that i
had to
you know the the things that i'm a very
introverted person
but i'm very sharpened in my
extroversion because
i had to go out and get a job like you
know as soon as i was legal to like go
go out and start selling clothes and
start being
more social and start you know all these
things so
we're built off of who we were when we
were children
but we do disconnect from this fact and
we can't seem to face it and we have
i mean i i i know i know people who
just in in and they'll never they'll
never openly speak about it like like
you or i would
who you know were were sexually abused
when they were younger
and like it clearly affects them it
clearly
gives them things that they have to deal
with it gives them you know
whether it's alcoholism whether it's
anger problems whether it's
you know closed off and these aren't
things to be insecure about these are
real
you know like i have nothing but
compassion for these people i totally
get it
um but we we can't seem to couple
who we are in every moment with the
things that have been done to us because
if we were able to do that if we were
able to bring that into our
our noticed awareness we could be like
oh
i don't have to prove anything to this
person i don't have to act out this
thing
i can accept love from this person
they're not going to hurt me just
because i've been hurt in the past
doesn't mean that this person is going
to hurt me or
whatever it is so do you think that
do you think i guess do you think we're
dealing with
a traumatized society that doesn't know
they're traumatized
i'll tell you that my boyfriend is a
very big proponent he's
um west indian so he's a very he
believes that
white people are the majority of people
who are mentally ill
and as many times as i want to have the
argument that just like there are
i'm sure there's so many reasons i know
black people who are in therapy so like
i don't know i don't i can't talk about
the racial statistics but
i think people what you're talking about
i think people
just want to be seen and that's a huge
thing that i do
and it's a heart people are so
surprised when you see them and like
just like we're talking about
when someone comes at you with a surface
level conversation
and i'm like trying to figure out like
where their line of thinking comes from
and i'm like
like how are you like how did you grow
up did you grow up around here or like
did you move a lot as a child like where
did
where is this coming from and they're
like huh
you're like trying to push away the
parts that aren't them like hey you
don't
where are you where are you in there
yeah
like i wanna see you like i wanna see
like
there's this thing about us that's just
blocking each other from understanding
like
i wanna what like we were talking about
the foggy glass like
i wanna like wipe away what's blocking
it and like
figure out what you actually look like
and what you actually
seem like and i think it comes
a lot from understanding yourself to be
able to understand
people and i feel like just recently i'm
really starting to understand myself
like you're saying taking a snapshot of
your identity
just recently like in the last week i've
taken a snapshot of myself and i've been
like
this is [__] awesome like this person
yeah
this person i'm building is [__]
awesome like
i'm learning how to manage my stress i'm
learning how to
be more present i'm learning how to
think about myself more and think about
understand when i'm projecting onto
someone rather than like their
experience is coming on to me
and just so there's a so like
the annoying thing if someone were to
call me annoying
now like i'm either doing something i
know is annoying
or it's not annoying and so what you're
saying doesn't affect me
or if it's annoying to you just like not
my problem
there is not anyone can call me anything
and it doesn't affect me because i know
i'm not that thing
the only way it affects you is if you're
insecure about yourself and not sure
maybe i am this thing
maybe i am ugly but like if someone came
up and called me fat and just like
called me fat all the time
i'm not gonna get upset and think i'm
fat i know i'm not fat
i'm gonna get upset because this person
keeps calling me fat like why am i gonna
be around a person who keeps calling me
fat
like you know like i'm not gonna get
insecure and stuff like that i'm not
gonna look at my body and be like oh my
god maybe i am
fat like i don't associate like you
can't call me
anything that i don't associate with and
upset me because i'm in control of my
reaction to it and my reality
well thoughts from other people can
really get sticky
inside of us like they can be you know
someone calls you annoying that's
something you hold on to you know look
at a kid for example you know if you if
you bully a kid or there's like some
traumatizing like where
six kids team up and just really bully
someone that's enough to like
[__] up their life look at justin ren i
think we both watched that broken
podcast
i mean he's talking about he goes to
this party that they told him
this sounds like a tv commercial or
something like where at the end they're
gonna show the
the duracell battery guy and his mom
hugging him or something like
he goes to a party and they told him it
was a dress-up party so he made like
this cool
like transformers outfit out of
cardboard boxes or something like that
walks into the party nobody's wearing
costumes except for him
everyone's laughing at him he's
devastated he runs away and he's like
traumatized like he has like suicidal
thoughts as a 35 year old man
like dealing with counseling dealing
with addiction all these things because
of that moment he believes
i mean holy [__] so
so growth growth is this powerful thing
and it's not just like maturity happens
on its own i think this takes work but
you can
not take what other people say to be the
only truth like like their opinions of
you just belong in their head
like that's the only place they're in
and you don't have to accept them you
don't have to hear them you don't have
to put them into your head
but sometimes they get sticky sometimes
it's like someone so one person says
you're annoying and it's like
for the next six weeks everything you do
you're a little more timid because he's
like i want to be the annoying person
you know like but so much of it too can
be them projecting on to you
like maybe people were calling me
annoying because they have learned that
like
doing these things are annoying to other
people other people have called them
being
them annoying for doing certain things
or something like that and so they see
me doing something and they're like
you're annoying
but it's really them projecting on to me
that
they were being annoying you know what i
mean hurt people hurt people
so i'm not gonna say my entire
experience was people projecting on me
i'm
i was certainly annoying when i was
younger but and i'm certainly annoying
now like
even times where i saw a funny meme the
other day that was like
sometimes even i'm like girl calm down
and
it's so true like there are times when
we were talking about um trying to take
life less seriously
and so there are times when i'm just so
upset about something whatever
ridiculous and i take a step back and
i'm like
come on give me a break girl like
why are you upset about this thing it's
not a big deal yeah
relax like um my boyfriend and i like to
match when we go out
and sometimes he just changes his mind
and wears a different outfit
and i used to be like yeah exactly
i'm like so upset and i'm like literally
like i planned my whole outfit and
like all these things are going through
my head and you just and
and then i'm just like i don't look cool
without you looking cool and then i'm
just like
hold on a second who [__] cares
like who cares who cares if we're
matching
like it's such a yeah that moment where
you're like
oh yeah oh yeah okay i can just let go
and then also the tension in your body
where we hold all of our emotions in our
body and all of a sudden just
huh oh yeah and you could laugh and
you're right
yeah it's just like like i was making
the
art for our podcast and i'm just like
what would be so funny
and i i have that photo of you on stage
where you're kneeling down
and i was like i have a photo of me
nailing down too and so at first it was
like a squad photo of you and i kneeling
next to each other
and i was like what if we were in space
this is
more far out needs more far outness
and then i turned you upside down and i
was just like
we need some helmets on here and they'll
like throw an airplane even though it
doesn't make any sense in space but
you know just stuff like that like the
size of the airplane i don't know if it
exists that's a big [__] airplane
listener if you're if you're listening
right now look at the the podcast album
aren't
brielle made for us that's what we're
talking about
it's just like and it's just it's so
funny and so ridiculous and it doesn't
make any sense and it's just like
i feel like so much of
like my job that i do and so many
people's frustration
and you know like i have a lot of work
on my plate
and person in charge of all the work
that i do is like
you have a lot of stuff and i'm stressed
about the amount of things that you're
doing
and i'm like i don't know why you're
stressed
it's not your stuff to work on it's not
he's like i feel like
you know i want to see this thing and i
want to you know xyz and i'm just like
it's my stress i don't know why you're
stressed about it just like
you know i just i think
it's just we need to be less serious
like it's not
our team gets so uptight about this and
that and
you know all these things god
maybe some people's way of being
their version of of empathetic and i
don't mean to disavow
let's let's lose your their version
let's just say their version of empathy
like
how they've learned to be empathetic
what if sometimes that is
feeling people's stress for them
like that's how they communicate empathy
or or
or wait is that is that apathy no
empathy there's sympathy and empathy
right so empathy is trying to feel the
other person's emotion yeah so so when
someone
they recognize like they don't innately
feel
like oh my gosh like like how can i help
i've experienced this i don't want you
to feel
like this much struggles i have instead
of that that approach
they say i'm going to be stressed
as if that takes away some of your
stress or or as if that makes you feel
more validated
maybe that maybe communicating that
they're stressed
makes the other person feel more
validated if they do get stressed almost
like hey if you're stressed it's okay
but that's just not like a healthy
coping mechanism that's just not really
how to show
compassion and empathy that's so true
because
you know if someone's upset or having
like an anxiety attack you never want to
get anxiety on their behalf because
making yourself stressed out i'm with
you bro i'm stressed too
start looking at pictures of your ex
right it's not gonna help it's just like
you need to be the calm one and that's
always where i come from whenever
someone comes to me with like stress or
anxiety i'm just like
let's think about like the
positive or like the grateful or
the like where do you come out of it
or maybe some people just need to feel
it sometimes you know like it's not
what's the solution it's just that you
just want to be heard
and some people just want to be listened
to
and like maybe they just need someone to
talk to
i've had a friend recently they're going
through a lot of stuff and it's just
like they just need
someone to talk to it's not like how can
we solve this how can we make it better
how
like what can we do or how could you
have not been in this situation how can
you
improve in the future not focusing on
this self-improvement
just just wants to talk about it
you know and i i don't know i
i agree that just getting stressed on
someone else's behalf
i don't think that's the way to do it
because that's not the way i
i'm not gonna i'm not gonna make myself
upset
i'm not gonna have my life experience be
harder because yours is yeah i want mine
to be great
and making my life experience great
is making others experience great
because then i'm surrounded by
glowing people so that's all i want to
do is just
make other people's experience great
right so at all times you're almost
trying to
figure out like what what are you
feeling right now you know that's that's
kind of like how uh
do you know your personality type
brielle like your uh
okay i know what you're talking about
but i haven't no yeah i know that that
stuff is a little far-fetched for some
people too but i
i i'm an infj and
i i think that i'm always
you know subconsciously trying to figure
out how someone feels like trying to
like i'm one of those people who who
i feel anyway this might be grandiose or
you know self validating or something
but
i i feel as if i can always like hey
what's up man you're talking to someone
and then like i can be like
are you good like like i i
i get the expression of of their of
their
personness of their humanity you know
i feel like i get like little signals
from their soul even if they're feeding
me some other [__] you know because
i've done that same thing
so i think that i can like relate with
it or see when it's happening
so i'm i i'm always trying to to figure
out where they're really coming from not
without the projections not the armor
not the boundary you know
i'll respect their boundaries not the
barriers rather um
but always trying to navigate in the
reason why i'm always trying to navigate
is because i want to insert compassion i
want to
generally want their want their this
this
um you know confrontation this
communication this conversation to be
better and more fruitful for the other
person but it's also just this
like i feel like that's what we should
be doing with each other is trying to
push each push
aside each other's [__] you know
like if someone if one of my homies is
coming in and they're freaking out and
they're they're in a bad mood and
they're going off like
you know at some point i gotta be like
my guy
chill you're good what's up yeah what's
going on yeah like what talk to me like
let's
let's turn off this [__] microphone
let's turn off this camera like what's
going on talk to me like let's
let's go over to let's go over here for
a second you know or or whatever
it's always like the core of what i want
to bring to the table of friendships and
companionships and interactions with
you know co-workers or whatever it is i
want to cut through the [__]
and and be like what's up man what's
what's trying to come out here
what's what's behind this these layers
that you're trying to put up
that you are unconsciously thinking you
don't even know you that you're doing it
but i think so much of it comes from you
personally understanding yourself
like i know that i do so much work on
myself and i understand myself so much
that
i've gone through this problem and this
is how i got out of it this
is you know i i encountered this and
whatever obstacle or whatever challenge
and like this is how i navigated and
then i see other people who are trying
to navigate the same things
and sometimes it's helpful not to say
this is the solution
but here was my solution here's how i
navigated
and they can try it on and they can see
if it works and sometimes it doesn't
work you know some people just think
very differently
and that's something i've learned is
that people think differently than me
than i do you know and they have just
comple
it's something i've gotten from
traveling is just that
people just think differently they think
of other things they don't think of
some things that you do they view the
world differently
they view people differently they view
family differently
they've you know it's just things like
that it's just
people can be so so different and
i you know when i think anything when i
think anything
that's my way of thinking it that's
unique to me
there are a lot of people probably in
the culture that i come from
that i can relate to and think similarly
but people in other cultures just might
not even consider it
or they might that might be the center
of what they consider
and all other things like are around it
you know and so
like some in some cultures family is a
huge deal
in some cultures you leave your family
very young and
like you're it's you know like animals
with um like birds they just kick them
out of the nest and like go fly and
figure it out
yeah yeah and meanwhile in like spanish
countries
it's like family forever and big family
and family dinner
every night and you know it's just so
important and so
there's just all these different
dynamics and people and so
what how to bring it back um like
just people experiencing different
things
i want to not help their
help them experience it but at least
give them like here's how i've
experienced it and how i've gotten
through it
and that just that comes from being in
pain and i can
i can show you my path because i've been
there
like i've this is how i've navigated and
figured it out
but all of that comes from you
understanding yourself
before you can try to understand someone
else because there's no way
you can think of like what makes you an
angry person what makes you
quick tempered what makes you you know
um
sarcastic what makes you this type of
person
you don't even have that thought process
until you think about yourself that way
what makes me an optimist what makes me
where did i get this from what makes me
grateful
how do i you just you
can't you can't look at other people and
analyze them
in that way until you analyze yourself
in that way
right yeah i think it makes life so much
more interesting too it really because
everything becomes fascinating i
remember jim carrey actually he's talked
about like some sort of
uh podium speech or interview or
something i've heard from him um
his his desire to be so funny and so
um obtuse and um uh
you know perpetually acting to be the
funny guy to be the one to make
everybody laugh
was because his i think it was his mom i
think was either
sick or very depressed she was very sad
when he was young
and so he he turned it when he was from
a young age he turned his job was like
i'm gonna make mom laugh i'm gonna make
her smile
and like that you know that's projected
this huge trajectory of his entire
career
and it's kind of developed into who he
is so you know
i'm sure he didn't realize these things
until he's like an older man
he you know he didn't he didn't come up
until he probably thought like i wonder
why i am
why am i always trying to make everybody
laugh like you know there is the answer
of look you know i just want to make
other people smile but there's there's
layers deep again with the layers of of
when did you learn these things was it a
coping mechanism was it a
you know is it good is it serving you so
he could look okay i'm making everybody
laugh
that's a good thing you know that seems
pretty good but am i doing it at the
expense of my own
true emotions am i shutting them down so
you know he realizes
i and he didn't say all this i'm going
off my own rant on this he just
communicated
that his mom was sad and he wanted to
make her laugh but
we we have to kind of look at who we are
and why we are who we are as an older
person
and not not justify it
not find blame not
victimize ourselves and this is even
cultural past right you know sometimes
we get caught up in that
in in like i am the way i am
because of these things that happened to
me because these things happen to my
family blah blah like well if they
aren't helpful to you and the culture
around you right now like how can you
shift them
if they're not bringing you joy if
there's things that you're holding on to
if you're still trying to make everybody
laugh but you're just [__] sad and
what you need right now is to feel some
real emotions for a couple months
then being happy for everybody around
you is not working for you
it's not fully working so um
yeah yeah i think it's i think it's very
fascinating to see
and helpful for people so helpful to not
avoid
um looking at why we are the ways that
we are
you know i think it's hard
hard to confront yourself you know it's
hard to
if you're upset about something why are
you upset
like why is it getting to you what is it
or or not even you know like someone's
doing something why is it upsetting to
you
do you want to be doing it do you hate
that you
do you hate the thought of you doing it
do you
hate the thought of them doing it do you
like what it where does it come from
like what
where and it's it's just hard to
confront yourself and
i don't even know if i don't even know
if people get to the place of like
i don't want to confront myself i feel
like there's just
not even a conscious thought of like i
can confront myself
you know what i mean and i like what you
said about
so much of your personality and
experience can come from
one thing when you're younger because
definitely a lot of my personality comes
from
a dream i had when i was younger and
like my whole
um yeah my whole
my whole dream about um
like i had to i was in this
i was in this like dark place i was very
young i was probably
maybe not very young um
i want to say i was like 15
15 or 16. something like that and um
no i had to be younger than that but um
no i think it was around like 16 or 17.
um
i was i had a dream that i was in this
like dark
place and there were these faceless men
standing around
me and they were making me shoot myself
and
i had to like i they were just like
pressuring me and pressuring me and
pressuring me and i was just i think i
was sitting on the ground
and there was like a spotlight on me and
just these faceless
seven faceless men in suits and they
were just
like i don't even think they were saying
anything it was just i was in the
situation that i needed to shoot myself
and i had to shoot myself and i had to
do it i had to do it i had to do it
and i shot myself in the stomach and i
felt myself die like i felt cold and
warmth and just
falling and all the things i didn't
experience
and all the thoughts i didn't think and
all the thoughts i did think
and what was right and what was wrong
and people i'd miss and all the stuff i
didn't get to
experience because i died so young and
all this kind of stuff and
when i woke up i had sleep paralysis and
i couldn't move
and i thought i was literally dead like
i couldn't open my eyes and
i couldn't move and i i had just killed
myself and i was like this is it like
i am really dead and i eventually woke
up and i was sleeping next to my brother
and i like looked around and i have been
[Music]
i have been present and grateful for the
moment
and will never let another person leave
without making sure this moment was good
i will never do that again because like
that was such a powerful dream for me
and such a powerful experience like
anything can happen at any moment and
i will not let you go or let me go
without making sure that this is good
and we are good and
there's nothing left unsaid and i was
myself and we both did the best that we
could in the situation
and that's that's entirely who i am and
it's just from that one dream
that happens i remember us talking about
this we
we were i think we were working the show
over in disney world um like
2019 and we were talking about this i
remember because i and i i feel so
profound because i literally got chills
when you're retelling me again and i
think i got it when we were walking
around too in disney world
like uh wow it's so crazy
you know when i asked earlier about um
you know kind of your mystical
experience or or a
conscious altering experience i i think
that that would actually kind of fall
into what i was kind of trying to point
at
these are experiences that you
afterwards you're a changed person your
perception of who you are and what
you're going to do or how you see things
or how you approach other people or
or how you just how you conceptualize
your your reality and how that controls
who you are and your identity
these things are changed um
okay let's not crush it what what is
that what is that like like
not just an nde not just a near-death
experience like you experience this in
the in the
you know the astral dream world realm
which astral projection is very real
lucid dreaming is very real um people
like
i haven't experienced it yet but there's
people who oh my god you can go on crazy
reddit
sinkholes whatever but this is a real
thing that can be experienced not not
necessarily a place
as we would think of it as a physical
place but it's a place within collective
consciousness that like people can see
go through in dreams and experience
similar things or
or certain events i mean this event
changed who you are
i had my similar events of you know when
i first started
all these things what suddenly made me
like go
the [__] am i doing what like why am i
doing things like this what is
yo it was like this this waking up
moment was i've talked about it on
before on here before
but i had um i was just like casually
doing
too many like party drugs and stuff and
i literally was behind the wheel
i had i had my girlfriend at the time in
the past receipt and i remember
i had to i had a couple too many drinks
i wasn't drunk
but i had more than i normally would
choose to have and still have my keys on
me
and i remember taking a bump this was
years ago i took took a a bump of blow
and and i and i was like suddenly i had
this coming to i mean it wasn't as like
near
i didn't have like people around me
telling me to kill myself like i'm not
trying to downplay i know this is very
not the same thing but the same your
experience is your experience
right okay thank you for validating um i
i had this sudden
like like this little it reminds me of
the movie soul just like this little
thing that floated in
of like i did it and i was like
what the [__] like what am i doing dude
like why would i make this
normal to just do in front of this purse
like what is like
i'm splitting my life with her like what
am i giving to this per you know just
all these profound things start sinking
in and um you know just like painful for
months afterwards because it just made
me look at all the things that i was
doing that i didn't like that i was
doing
but what what i'm what i'm asking
gabrielle
and we can get ethereal with this and i
know there's not really an answer but
it's interesting
to contemplate what is that what is this
thing that
in the human condition in within the
human experiment we have here
where suddenly this little like flicker
of something can change your perception
of of
it's just like this little light
particle floats into your brain and it
says like
hey turn around and look at yourself
there you are
and then it leaves you and then you have
then it's then it's like now
figure out your life on your own you
know
i don't i don't know what it is but it's
those are
the turning points of us as people and
they're those are part of the experience
and i think if you don't
have those things you're a shell of a
person
and there are definitely people we run
into that are that way
they've never experienced strife
they've never experienced you know
something difficult they've never been
too stressed out or even if they have
they've never
sat down and thought about it you know
so
i'll give you an example my brother was
in a car accident
and nothing bad happened he was totally
fine
it was technically his fault but because
we live in florida we have a no fault
rule
so he didn't get a ticket um there's
the person who was in the accident as
well
she tried to sue for like she said her
neck hurt um
i don't i don't know how badly her neck
hurt
um but she was alive and
my brother was alive and the person in
the car with my brother was alive
and um my brother
he had a new car and he was able to get
enough money from like when his car was
totaled
and insurance gave him basically the
same amount of money that his car
cost so he bought a new car another new
car
and i wanted him
to come out of that experience
completely changed like
i could have killed this person i need
to pay more attention
i need to be more present i you know
like thank goodness
i'm alive all these kinds of things and
he didn't
he didn't come out of it like that he
got a new car that my parents paid for
and he
i don't think he texts and drives but
like i'm pretty sure he pays attention
when he drives i don't know how
i haven't been in the car with him since
because i'm just scared
but he doesn't like have an aura of
gratitude
to like like the fact that he's alive
and
he just i talked to my dad about it and
it's just
he doesn't some people don't think that
way some people don't
like analyze the experience and
until they do though right like
like there's there's i feel like there's
there's probably i'm sure we both know
i don't know i'm sure we both know a
couple people who have had like
they're they're living unconsciously to
some aspect or they're
at least that yes yeah
but but but they had a sudden like
like that situation what you and i are
looking for is like why didn't your
brother have this sudden like little
flicker of
jesus why wasn't that the moment that
did it for him
like why wasn't that his life-changing
experience but then i wonder how many
moments have i had before that one
moment where i'm like
doing a bump of blue because i had too
many tequila shots or whatever
like like why was that the
the pre the press why was that the the
jumping board the the
and there's there's so many times where
it's like you hear the same thing over
and over again
until that one time when you hear the
same thing and it just hits you
correctly
and you're like wait a minute that's
what it means
that's like my favorite part about
philosophy or listening to any sort of
philosophical thought is i'll find
myself listening to the same lectures
they're just
i'm letting the youtube algorithm just
like numb my mind and so i'm clicking on
one i'm like
i've listened to somebody else upload
the same one but call it something else
but i'll listen to it
again and it sounds like a completely
different talk because i'm at a
different point in my life
you know maybe six months later it could
be more profound so
you've apparently you've got to be ready
to follow the path
to actually follow the path of something
you have to be
you have to be ready to receive it you
know like there's some
how many times do you watch something
that you watched as a kid and you're
like oh my god all this stuff went all
over my head like i had no idea and i
didn't
like i'm so glad i learned these things
i was watching a little einsteins thing
the other day
i was like i watched this video when i
was younger i
like i i thought
okay so let me i'll go to religion i
grew up jewish
so now that i'm learning
about a lot of the things that they
teach jewish children
i'm like that's part of who i am that's
like that's and i had no idea i like
learned that
in hebrew school or in judaica or
anything like that
i had no idea like that's the reason i
am the way i am
is wholly because i'm jewish and like i
learned all these things when i was
younger
but i had no idea what they meant and
now that i'm like relearning them and
rehearing them and seeing how they
relate to my religion i'm like oh my god
this formed my personality like these
are
parts of who i am and it comes from
xyz and it's just it's so crazy to me
that
it just it just matters when you hear it
and how
how ready you are to receive it how well
you know yourself
like you've tried on all these hats and
now they fit differently
and you fit differently and now you hear
these things and you can try it on again
and you can be like huh like maybe i can
take a little bit of this or
you know it means something different or
so much more or so much less you know
like
maybe i don't think of this as as as
important as i thought it was you know
you know that's something i think
powerful about
obviously you know having these little
instances of flipping your whole
perception
about everything and questioning
everything that's of course a huge plus
but i think
i think our our
age group even or maybe it dude maybe
it's just like
how younger people are now you know we
change so much because of our our
technology in the internet and these
things like
the younger generation is very very
different
and grew up very different their
perceived reality is very different than
like
you know a boomer aged person you know
yeah trying to use boomer as an
offensive term i
don't mean any offense to any older
people um
but it's just like a generalization but
so maybe maybe our our technology
and our i mean i don't know i always
want to see things through the lens of
like how technology is changing us
but there there does seem to be i mean
if i didn't have technology if i didn't
have all these youtube lectures and all
these audio books and all these even
just books even just writ literature
not lit literature writ literature uh
like i i wouldn't ever i mean there was
nobody in my life to ever teach me these
these sort of like look at why the way
you're thinking and and what
why do you think about it and why is
that interesting to you and
so i think that our culture now our
younger culture
we [__] change so much like every
month like all people on my podcast
and like two months later they're
they're like i'm not even that same
person i don't even
like i don't want to listen to that
because i don't think any of those
things anymore i've just changed
and and i think the same thing i'll
listen to myself and it'll be like dude
it's a week later and i think i think
differently on that
and that's hard to do you know with like
the internet is not forgiving they're
like you're inconsistent i'm not
listening to you
you're weird you're unsure of what
you're talking about or whatever or
they'll hold you to what you
felt and said yeah yeah like an
interview like so so you said this
and i assume it to mean this and you're
like i don't really
fully believe that but in that context i
think here's what i was talking about
anyway and here's how i feel it now at
this age so again we're back to where we
were at the beginning
we forget at all times that this life
this this conscious experience
is fluid it's always changing it's water
and we're moving towards evolution
is behind us or whatever like pushing us
we are evolution
pushing us flowing through and changing
us and
and maybe we're just changing at a
faster rate the younger people because
of technology because because of the
internet we're just changing at a faster
rate or we're able to change or more
open to change
more than we were in the past um
[Music]
i i don't know exactly the point of what
i was trying to say but
i think that we definitely um like with
the
existence of like the podcasts and
audiobooks and things like that
especially like reading people's memoirs
and just relating they're relaying a
story and i'm relating to them and how
they went through their
challenges and how they got through it
and how they became this author who
wrote a book
like we have access to that because of
technology and i'm able to see
like oh they did that they think that
way i don't really think that way
or i do think that way or that's a great
idea
or you know i want to i want to
institute those kinds of things in my
life and
start doing that too or i don't agree
with that
and i'll never raise my children that
way
or you know things like that and i think
books i've been reading are great for
that but it's just
it's a lot of like trying on it's a lot
of
i don't know that i'm sure technology
changes us
yeah i'm sure technology changes us but
it's because we have so much
access to different people like
to relate to and you know like
we started i you asked me this question
last time how did i start on social
media and my answer was that i started
on myspace
i started doing those surveys in the
myspace bulletin board
and it was people would post like what
color do you like and what grapefruit
and what
what fruit are you and what you know all
these things and you would just read
how you relate to somebody else or like
what they answered and whether you agree
or not and then you would do it and
other people could see how you felt
about all those questions and some of
them were like 180 questions long
and you're like what do you have to do
in middle school that you could be
sitting there for 180 questions and then
do another one one after the other
yeah you got your msn messenger window
over in the background you're swapping
back
in your survey i definitely did that
yeah and it's just like
what are you doing what are you up to
how do you like oh that
middle school test was hard you're just
constantly relating to people
and so much of the experience of
being able to reach so many people and
so many personalities and see so many
people's lives and
we can compare ourselves to each other
but we can also
like try each other on we can see these
luxurious people with so much money and
like
try it on like would i like that do i
want to have a lot of money would i like
this type of life and then we see people
who are in the trenches like reporters
and stuff who
go and do the hard things and try and
find out the truth like
do i want to do that do i want to defend
a subject do i want to defend a group of
people do i want to help
this you know type of thing and then we
see people who
are ignorant and they just you know live
their lives
in their own life and we see that like
maybe i shouldn't be thinking of things
as much maybe i should
maybe i should do what they're doing
maybe i should you know like
not really consider xyz and we just
we have so much access we can try on
so much and i don't know if people
realize that they're
doing that yeah i i don't know i don't
think we realize how
profound those things like like a
myspace survey
it's this thing that's behind you know
it's a cool little blue app or
you know it's this cool little page that
that hipster and like edgy people get to
go on and there's
you know you get to me for example my
profile picture gets to be me laying
down the train tracks and it's a black
and white photo
and i've got my like skeleton gloves on
and they're fingerless and whatever
like i get to express myself through
this cool little outlet
but also it's this profound thing that
we get to
see we're given you know the phones and
our cameras and
in the internet in our laptops and stuff
they're kind of like a window
to see other parts of the world like we
get to in our lived experience in our
homes here
where for hundreds and thousands of
years the human experience has only been
like
dude if you don't know him inside your
community unless you're going to go on
like some
some the organ trail and like meet all
these people and
and experience all these different
cultures along the way or whatever and
all these hardships and change by those
like it's a new thing to so rapidly
and so quickly be able to question
or wonder or try on i love your use of
that word
um other people and even me with
you know when after i had that profound
moment moment in the car where i'm like
what the heck am i doing
um it started leading into these this
escalade of
i was watching i would start watching
lectures i would watch you know sam
harris and eric weinstein and brett
weinstein and jordan peterson
and um you know all these variants of
joe rogan all these inspiring people and
i would start to take like
well i like this about him i like this
about him and i've always kind of been
like that anyway
but this internet just [__] whoo gave
me nos man like i was able to just i'm
easily inspired that's like one of my
favorite little catch phrases like i
just want to wear it on my shirt it's
easily inspired
that's me but i think all of us are so
inspired by all these little things
we're trying to build ourselves
and and make ourselves into all these
all these
all these things so we can i don't know
like just
live and experience all this stuff we're
trying to cram pack
so much stuff into a short-lived life
that we're accelerating too fast and we
need to
remember to slow down and be grateful
for what we do have because we're so
obsessed with what we don't have
that it's making us think over there um
but if you want to take it back if you
want to bring it full circle
um half circle um if you look at those
people who are
talking about like the news that they
watch and they're upset about
you know gdp like you mentioned and
whatever they're upset about like
that can also just be them trying that
on like i'm trying on like
caring about the news and caring about
politics and i see all of these people
who are upset about this thing so like
i think i should be upset about this
thing they don't really
know about it but like they see that
other people are doing it so it could
just be them
trying it on and when you're like it
doesn't make any sense
like hopefully they can sometimes you do
stump people
and they're like you know it doesn't
make sense what i'm saying
you're right i don't understand it so
it's
a lot of our experience is just like
everyone trying
each other on and in doing that figuring
out who we are what we are
what we like and what we don't like yeah
okay because i feel like
you're blowing my mind if you're like
i'm i'm thinking
you know people like you and i were
talking earlier about we're trying to
see
like we're trying to you know like
what's what's the real you i know you're
in there you know
it's what what happens in a lot of these
situations
i think because i have compassion for
these people i i don't think like oh
you're a [__]
boris loon like what are you talking
about you know like people come at me
and and what i'm seeing
what i basically want to tell them is
the costume you're wearing it's not you
like the the cost that one doesn't hey
bro i know you're trying it on but
what i want to say to them down in there
i want to be like
hey bro the the the outfit that you put
on the the costume that you're trying
out you're just trying it out i get that
but
it's not you it's taking over you a
little bit too much and i think i see
the real you in there and i love you
you know they just don't have like
yeah they just don't have like something
to hold on to so they're just like
looking for it like
a lot of people are just trying to form
their baseline to figure out who they
are and so
they look to whatever they're consuming
and they you know like if you watch the
news 24 7 you're going to become a news
junkie and so you just
are upset about everything the news
tells you you should be upset about and
you're just trying to find your base
and a lot of that is just like once you
realize
i mean i hope once you watch the news
enough
you realize that like life isn't the
news
so many people like i i'll have the my
dad is grateful for me
because he watches the news all the time
my dad is 70 years old
and he is like the cliche like
china's coming for us like i'm reading
this book about china and
china's china buyers yeah and so
a lot he's like people in this country
are just so
dumb and they're you know like they're
yeah and they're just you know whatever
mean and uh stupid
stupid and mean and uh
whatever just like negative things about
people and i'm like everyone i know is
pretty great
everyone i'm surrounded by everyone i
see on the news yeah they're a little
crazy
but everyone in my real experience
pretty cool
i've never really encountered anyone
who's like blatantly an [__]
like maybe they have been but it's
because they're upset about whatever and
in context it makes sense that they're
being an [__]
no one's ever just literally been like
done something mean for no reason and
outrageous
and it can be that i'm just not in the
areas where those people
are existing but for the news to make it
seem like that's the general population
i don't really agree with that because
my idea of the general population the
people who i experience the most
are all pretty great people wow yeah i
mean our perception really is flipped by
what we're constantly looking at like if
your window from your home
is you look out and it's like all right
i'm gonna go you know what we call the
news now it's like okay this is the news
and you watch it it's on msnbc and it's
on
you know fox or whatever the news
networks are like
what that is if you remove the word news
it's a window to look at people that you
don't like or it's a window to look at
things you don't like about people or
it's a window to look at
things that other people are saying are
wrong about
the bad other and so
in choosing to uh yeah yeah yeah
uh this i think it's i think it's
plato's cave
uh have you heard of i could be
butchering this and i would love if i
had a jamie jamie look it up leo's cave
but uh it's essentially like the
the story it's this uh kind of like
philosophical old story
um these people are looking like their
whole life and their whole community and
just through different generations they
grow up and
there's a rock wall
and on the other side of it is a fire
and so everything they see
is shadow they don't know about fire
they haven't discovered fire yet
but everything they see is these dancing
moving photos on this giant wall and
that's been their whole community and
they stay here and this is for hundreds
of years or whatever
i'm butchering this but you get the
picture and all they know is shadow and
then somebody finally like
yeah i'm gonna go i'm gonna leave the
cave i'm gonna go check out what's on
the other side and they go
and they're like oh there's there's a
fire over here oh
you guys what our gods are actually just
our shadows from our hands moving like
whatever
and and everybody in your community you
can you can't like you guys come over
here look no no it's see it's
when i move my hand and make the
butterfly and that's that's what we call
our gods and whatever
the whole so so what they're doing their
window to reality
is based off of like what they perceive
right here in front of them
and so what happens when we watch like
these
obsessive amounts of news i think is
that's what we
see like we're just watching shadows and
making that
our perception this is the reality of
what's happening in the world
these shadows are the only thing that
exists and then when someone comes along
and they're like bro no look at like
there's literally a fire and it's just
shadow puppets like trust me it's okay
this is it's actually not that bad
this [__] was more to life than just the
shadow people
like they don't want to hear it because
their whole reality their whole identity
too
is wrapped up in accepting you know if
you if you grow
up 45 years you're an elder of a
community for 45 years
and you're teaching every child like
here's the great god of
of dionysius and he's expressed through
this long tall shadow or whatever you
know and that's
that's what your reality is you don't
know anything else
someone comes along and they're like bro
none none of the things you believe are
real
follow me i'll show you nobody wants to
get up like nobody wants to be like
all right let let's unwind everything i
want to do that won't be scary or
maybe everything i know is wrong yeah
maybe everything i know is wrong nobody
wants to ask that holy [__] what a
painful thing
i had an experience the other day where
it was such a
i felt so dissociated i don't even know
if it's that people are obsessed with
the news or like obsessively watching it
but they do just associate
their entire view of our country and the
world
through the news like the news shows us
the majority and what everything is
going on rather than us looking at like
our experience because we don't
experience everything so we like look to
other sources
and we see on the news and the news
should be a pretty good source of
our general experience as americans and
we should be able to look at the news
and see
like this is what other americans are
experiencing this is what's going on in
the world
maybe not the case but recently i had
the experience um
i think it was when the um capitol
building was being stormed
i saw that on the news or literally like
someone sent it to me because i haven't
been watching the news
and someone sent it to me and i was like
oh [__] like
people going nuts people really go nuts
and then i put my phone down and it like
left my head because
like in my apartment things are cool
like there's i'm not in washington
there's literally nothing i can do it's
it doesn't affect me like i it
if i wanted to be upset about it like as
upset as i could get about it
nothing is going to change so like i'm
just not going to burden myself with
those feelings and so
i saw it i forgot about it my boyfriend
comes over and he opens the door
and he's like it's [__] crazy out
there and i'm like
i'm looking out the door like what's
going on is there yeah i'm like looking
around like are you being followed
what's happening
yeah i'm like what's happening and he's
like no i mean like what's happening in
dc and i'm like
oh oh like hold on a second
okay who cares
i mean like not who cares but like
like how does it i was i was so taken
aback by him being like it's crazy out
there and i'm like what's going on like
in our experience what's happening and
he's just like no not
not us but it's you know
i i recall what i did that same day
which this
is i mean uh i mean this is um like a
month ago at this point about a month
um if not exactly a month um
i i remember i read some stuff about it
or like people started
posting on on social media and then so i
you know i looked up a couple things
and i saw a couple of videos and this is
as it was still going on and i was like
mother of pearl like what this is crazy
and i didn't
continue like obsessing about it like i
did kind of my information i'm like you
know it's this kind of
well this another thing whatever but i
did go right downstairs
and i interrupted my my roommate who was
who was working he works remotely and
he's a coder and i was like bro have you
seen like what's going on over in
washington dc and we kind of talked
about it so
so there is a part of us that feels the
need to
know because because biologically
we've learned we want to connect but we
also need to watch out for threats man
like
like okay if we're we're in tribes we've
got less than 150 people in our tribe
and we have um some nomad who just
wanders and we know him
oh yeah that's greg we see him every
couple years and he drops off until we
sell him our fur or whatever
and he comes and he's like there's a
pack of 50 hyenas
and they're about i don't know three
miles back they were heading our way
you know i don't just let you know just
letting you know we'd be like
oh sound the alarm like there's hyenas
coming you know
like it's it's a part within us that
we've learned through
through culture and in in through like
our being of who we are
as human society but i guess you're it's
being kidnapped now it's being
it's being it's being taken and thrown
in our faces and it's being used and
weaponized against us our
because we want to look out for our
family sorry i i interrupted you but we
want it we're trying to protect
if i'm a mother and i genuinely think
that
people in shirts and ties are going to
unzip their face
and they're actually a reptile and
they're going to kill my kids if that's
legitimately what i think
of course i'm going to react
dramatically to things like in
these the news and all these like q anon
and like all these rabbit holes on
youtube and all these things
articles and whatever and fake news
whatever
it convinces us convinces us that we
need to be
terrified it convinces us that we need
to watch out
i will say there's definitely i didn't
realize it but now that you're saying
this
i'm sure there was a part of that
experience
where i saw what was happening and i had
to think about whether it was a threat
to me
and i when i realized it wasn't a direct
threat like no one's coming to storm my
house my family's okay
everyone in my life is okay like
it's bad that that's happening obviously
i feel for the people it's happening to
but like
there's nothing i can directly do and
it's not coming for me
so then i can relax a bit and i i didn't
realize but you're right i think that's
something that like that was a thought
that crossed my mind that
is it a threat to me no okay we can be
okay
it's not happening to me but i think
that our culture right now
that's not what happens i think that we
can we can recognize i mean
the like we're we're very smart you know
we do understand like
okay i get that this isn't outside my
window
but i think that we we try to figure out
what could this mean
does this mean that the government is
doing this does this mean that
now there's gonna be riots in portland
and i live closer to porn there's gonna
be riots in seattle i live closer to
seattle and
and whatever our wheels get turning and
then we think our actions are like we're
basically doing preventative maintenance
we're like stocking up our bunkers
by like making sure this [__] ain't
coming at us but every single day
these news stations because it's what
sells and they're not even just like the
evil cabal who's trying to sell it it's
literally algorithms that are working
they're working us at this point the
algorithms are changing what we're doing
and what we're saying especially news
anchors
and [__] they're telling us like here's
what you should be afraid of and it's
formulating these big hypotheses of
uh within people's minds of how things
are going to play out in the next
whatever amount of years
and like
i i i love using the drunken the the
dunkin trestle
concept of uh i've said this multiple
times before on the podcast but
there's probably some dude right now
sitting next to a beautiful waterfall
who has no idea
how pissed off he's supposed to be right
now yeah like
it is that but then there we have this
very intelligent thing we have this like
really cool thing where i can see
exactly what's going on on a like a live
stream i can see what's going on in
china right now
in a live stream and they can see what's
going on in america right now
and if like it's interesting but it's
also
there's a part of me that's like making
you know if i was watching it like if
i saw a video being streamed of them
they
you know this is a corner that i don't
want to be in but
of china launching some rocket at us or
something we'd be like
oh [__] like i'm the one who saw it like
i need to let everybody know i need to
make sure all my family and friends know
that we're about to die because there's
a nuke coming or whatever
direct threat yeah yeah we have we so so
we have the inability
we have an inability to know whether
things are direct
threats or not right now like how can we
as a society as a culture
as um you know again i i just like
saying brothers and sisters like we're
all in this [__] thing together
like americans even like how do us as
americans
decipher like is this a threat is this
something that i need to
attack is this something i need to stamp
out is this something that's important
like what what's important how does this
how does this thing that's coming i
think
when and how will it ever possibly
affect my daily lived actual life
yeah and there's so much of like
how much of the news is what's actually
happening you know like maybe these bad
things that we see are happening
aren't you know like they're just being
portrayed as bad
or the other side is making them seem
worse than they are
or they are happening along with
other things that we're not seeing or
they are happening with things that we
could change if we had saw them
or you know just like our entire
experience is
skewed and so i was having a
conversation the other day with
um i was out at breakfast and we're
sitting there
and it's beautiful day outside during
coven
beautiful day there we're sitting right
next to a railing we were sitting
outside because she brought her dog
so i'm sitting there with her handsome
little puppy
and across from her and we're both like
very healthy people
and everyone in the restaurant is like
properly spaced out but like
having a great saturday morning people
in the park
just playing watching a dog like run
around this little girl
and just have so much fun this family
have so much fun and
i'm just like looking around and i'm
like this doesn't seem like the world
that the news
says it is you know like this doesn't
this is great like this is a beautiful
life and
everyone else around me seems to be
enjoying it i don't know what's going on
in their lives but like
everyone's smiling and everyone's
talking and everyone's complimenting the
dog
and everyone's just like happy to be
outside
like it doesn't it's not the reality
that i'm seeing on the news
you know yeah it's so
so how do we get less caught up with
this just
sack of misinformation and the sack of i
mean
basically i think what we need to get to
as a culture
is we need to stop believing any of that
[__]
like we need to i mean like
it's vastly unhelpful to be
most of the things that we care about on
a day-to-day basis
if you're someone who watches the news
if you're someone who's like even even
really up in like pop culture like
i even i'm someone who i really like i
like pop culture i like studying kind of
like what's
what's going on right now what's going
on oh like what did travis scott say
what did rihanna say what did
you know uh you know whoever i
i there is an enjoyable aspect to that
but
there's something in our brains that we
don't seem to remember like this is just
what a person with an agenda not
always evil just an agenda of their own
life of how they want to act things out
and do things and
achieve their own goals in their life
they just happen to be the ones that are
in this location with a camera
in the networks which are companies that
we watch
are choosing to put them on their
network that's not reality that's just
here's a way in which you could see the
world and we're believing that is like
this is truth
and everything else is fake news like
that an angle that's a camera angle bro
not
everything you remind me of the
difference between the medium and the
message
you know do you know what i'm talking
about i don't um
so the medium
is so the message is the content and the
medium is how the content is delivered
and so what you're saying is like this
you have a person who has a message but
the message is being delivered through
producers in a camera through their like
famous life
of their experience and like that's the
medium
that it's and you're receiving it like
on your cell phone
in your experience of life like
the medium is how you receive it and the
message is the actual context or the
actual like
what you should be receiving and so
maybe maybe that's i i've never thought
about it so maybe that's like a
something to consider that like the the
medium
of the news is not the message because i
have been ignoring the news and i don't
think that's healthy either like you
don't want to just ignore what's going
on
and so i'm trying to find this balance
of like
watching the news but watching with a
grain of salt you know like
understanding like this is what's going
on
how do i feel about it before i see how
someone else feels about it like
what is the medium i'm receiving it from
and like what's the actual
message i should get out of it you know
yeah i mean i feel like when you said
that because i find myself saying that
too you know i
i don't really absorb much news but then
i also go through phases of like
dude i can't just be totally oblivious
to what's going on in the world
but i kind of wonder if maybe
i should be more oblivious like me like
like i said we're
you know you got to understand what's
going on in the world well the people
who
they've now proven for many years the
people who are telling us what's going
on in the world and that which we should
care about
they're not i'm not gonna say they're
evil i'm not gonna say they're bad
they're a product of this like late
stage capitalism like it's
it's the way the way
the definition of news in like what it
should be
is not the same definition of what news
actually is
like what what is news to us and i could
even say
i can expand like maybe it's not the
exact same word it's not the same
terminology but like i legitimately get
my news
i listen to podcasts i listen to youtube
channels i have like
a lot the majority of the news that i
get in like the logical people that i
listen to
is from two evolutionary biologists who
live in portland
and like they talk about what's going on
in the world but other than that like i
don't really
i don't really mess with like the news
networks but
we have people who do mess with the news
networks that we have people who do
their entire reality their entire
view they're looking through one of
those kaleidoscopes you know and like
because what they see is completely
different reality than what i see
and i think we have to recognize how
much that actually
paints and controls and affects and
pulls our biological
emotions because our emotions are
actually felt in our bodies our like
their uh you know
our our emotions are experienced in our
body
rather i guess and we're able to you
know
look at virtual reality it's an
extension of what this stuff is we're
able to put on headsets we're able to
look through these windows
of of technology and it's able to
affect our biological meat vehicle here
and we have to we have to ask ourselves
like if we're constantly feeling
stressed out because of what we're
seeing through the windows we're looking
through we've got to be like
damn should i chill on looking through
these windows a little bit like or
is there a way to i can glance through
windows like with
with some sort of governor where i only
give myself 15 minutes a day to look
through these windows
because i know that i'm i'm going to
want to protect my family and i'm going
to get like addicted to making sure
there's no missiles in the sky so i can
protect my kids you know it's
i i'm trying to bring compassion to the
people who are so stressed out and so
they think that everybody's out to get
them and they think that like
china is trying to [__] kill us and
because i don't even know at this point
like who knows
it's all like it's all so complicated
but they tell us you can
like you can you see china and like can
trust them but like china's also like
putting on a facade and so much
propaganda and they like hide everything
from us and it's just like i don't
i don't know yeah i mean but but if we
were
in china and we're watching there i mean
everything we've been told
i've never been to china myself
everything we've been told is you know
the
you know like they are a you know
the chinese communist party but
what we know of as as as communists
is represented in our like
cocky american attitude of capitalism's
the best way you all need
this kind of democracy you know like
we're we're so stuck up
inherently as western that's just how
people with western minds
think like we are kind of like our view
of things is better
we can't look at benefits from other
ways
of of running you know civilizations so
jesus christ like what a what a a wild
thing we're experiencing here you know
like what a crazy really crazy thing
i think it goes back to the technology
you're talking about how much
how much should i expose myself to this
window that i'm looking through but we
have so much technology we have so many
windows to look into
and it can just be overwhelming and you
can say
i'll watch the news with a grain of salt
like i'll understand
this with a grain of salt but like do
you watch all of the podcasts that you
watch of the grain of salt
do you watch every youtube video with a
grain of salt do you watch
everything that you experience through
every little window you look into
every encounter you have with a person
like
they tell you one thing and their trust
you trust them so you believe them like
should you believe them is what they're
saying correct or is what they're saying
based on all the windows that they're
looking into
where does it come from and like at what
point at what like
how do we navigate you know there are so
many windows there are so many
and it's i don't know how to get the
people who are watching the news all the
time i don't know how to get them less
stressed because
they seem to live and i'm just looking
at like older people because like my dad
his friends my mom her friends
things that those people do just like
paying attention to the news all the
time like even when you know you
shouldn't do it
like tons of people when all the um
masks
stuff started coming out like just early
march
tons of people told me like i've had to
stop watching the news just because like
so much mask drama there's so much drama
about kova there's so much this there's
so much that and just like at some point
it's exhausting
it is exhausting yeah how much of like
the
how much of the news is news and then
how much of it is just like repetitive i
agree with you having a
like a time limit because at what point
are we just gonna keep talking about the
same
person did the same thing and it's so
frustrating
like are you gonna tell me what's
happening like
happening in the world and like people
are generally
more harmful to each other maybe i need
to look out for that
you know like um shootings are going up
in your area
like oh my god maybe i should be more
careful about that
until like i want to hear that stuff i
want to know what's going on i want to
know that like
yeah nukes aren't being launched at us
right now i wanna know what's going on
but like do i wanna hear
about someone who went out with a mask
or without a mask i mean
don't care do i wanna you know just like
i care about these things and like it's
good to know but like
at what point do you have enough stuff
that's good to know
you know like how much of it is just
just stop like
so much
it's hard that like so much is good to
know like you should
be informed but also
how much of being informed is actually
helping you
like how much time am i spending
wondering how i feel about donald trump
whereas that actually doesn't affect my
life
you know like i i think it's probably
most healthy to just
not ever think about the [__]
like yeah that that is what
i mean that we're we're drowning in
information drowning
in information and i think
because of all this information because
we have all these different companies
who are saying this one's the most
important no this one's the most
important and then we have these
algorithms who are saying
this is the most important because this
will get more people to watch it
and that we're like okay yeah listen to
that that one's the most important then
where we're fighting it's it's like we
only have 24 hours in a day
i mean it's hard enough to get done what
we really want to do
i mean like i i think like we get so
much crammed in nowadays like i'll watch
you know multiple lectures or like
listen to multiple podcasts
i'll get you know listen to a ton of
music get my own personal work done i'll
get workouts done
like you can get so much done in a day
but it's exhausting like it's it's
tiring
and you have to almost filter out like
okay i just don't have time
for this i don't have time to listen to
this like i i
i guess i hope that we exhaust ourselves
on this news
in some sense and or or they realize
um like where we're maddening our own
society
like the news
abraham like what what would you and i
say like if we had like
like snap of a thanos finger and i've
got you and i are at the head of
50 executives and they're like the
people who make the [__] calls and
news networks
or or the they're the investors or
whatever and we're like
listen y'all you don't see what you're
doing but you
are fabricate like you you you're
ripping apart the fabric of our
society's
lived experience and like ability to
relate to one another
here's what you can't be doing anymore
like what would we say to them like
i think there's a lot of it comes from
like there needs
to be news happening on this network at
all times like in case anyone tunes in
and i just like if there's not news
then there's nothing to be on like
black screen please like unless but it's
hard because like
people tune in at different times so you
always want to be talking about the same
things like did you hear about this
thing that happened this morning that
you weren't awake to hear about at 5 00
a.m like now you're here and we want to
talk about it but
if you've been watching since 5 a.m
you're like oh my god they've already
talked about this like just stop
so i don't know the answer but i think a
lot of it a lot of it comes from like
they want to just keep
they want to keep you informed but they
want to keep talking so that there's
more of a show and more money to make
and more viewership and
as long as they can keep the news going
all day then they can have people
watching
all day but right like if say that like
the news happens from
10 a.m to 12 p.m you watch it for two
hours a day
here's all the things that are going on
thanks we'll see you tomorrow
if there's like a news break like in
your area there's a mass shooting right
now like maybe that pops up on your
phone
and you like see it but there's no like
obsessing over
the news and i'll but then you know like
people
want things to say in the news cycle and
some things get skipped over and stuff
like that but i don't know like
do we need it to stay there like it's
hard to say because like we don't want
to just
pass over you know bad things that
happen like shootings that happens
in anywhere we don't want to just like
forget about them and then keep moving
on with our lives and not care about the
people that it happened to but also like
do we want to keep dwelling on it and i
don't know if it's dwelling like if
if we keep thinking about it and we keep
addressing it then
we can address the issue and hopefully
solve a problem
but like there are other things
that we just keep addressing and like
nothing's going to be solved by it and
it's not even worth continuing to
address so like
i don't know maybe if i had the answer
that would be just like scheduled news
times
like the newspaper you read the
newspaper and you're like oh [__] all
this stuff happened yesterday
okay read it got it yep
cool next day here's my name can you
throw it in the break room so someone
else can maybe read it
yeah and we can we can like talk about
it and stuff and we can
try and figure out the problem and if
it's something as insane as like
injustice and things like that like we
can band together and continue the
conversation but
for it to be like like nothing
is front page news every day or
that's not true but most things aren't
front page news
every day like you don't see like biden
as president
biden is president biden is president
there's constantly like something
new that's happening and so like
for the news networks to just continue
replaying the same things over and over
like they they eventually have to talk
about
something and so they just talk about
nothing
and like that's the part that's not news
and so i just like just turn it off
turn off the show like if there's no
news today there's no news like
the groundhog didn't see his shadow then
okay
thanks for letting me know hold on yeah
yeah like
i don't i don't know the answer i don't
know how to get people to be less
stressed
about it and i don't know i don't
it's just such like a grain of salt
thing you just
and that comes it comes back to
understanding like you have to
understand yourself
to understand what matters to you and to
be okay with like
if you see on the news that
i don't know a lot of people are acting
this way and believing this way and
storming the capitol building
don't surround yourself with people who
are ridiculous that would do
something so crazy like that and don't
be the type of person
that would encourage that and don't be
the type of person that would do that
and encourage the people around you to
be
understanding and positive people
and the people around you won't do that
and if everyone around them
and if everyone convinces one person
around them
to not be that type of person hopefully
we would have a better society of
better people you know like it starts
with us
i completely agree self-sovereignty is
the way and it's like the only
option that we have it's just each
individual needs to
look at their own train of thought and
look at their own addictions
to social media to news to these devices
and i'm saying that as someone who's
very addicted to social media i
definitely am always on this damn thing
too
you and i both you know it yeah 100 we
talk about this all the time
um but i think
i mean because as much as we want to say
like
hey snap out of it like you got to help
your friend snap out of it
gabrielle these people literally think
that
like they think that the this entire
democracy is being like the people who
stormed the capital a lot of them at
that time anyway they legitimately
had the feeling they had the belief this
is true
like our our democratic system is so
corrupt
that like the person the only real
honest person that we've ever had in
office
has now been they've been frauded out of
the election like they legitimately
believe that
like there's this evil all this stuff
going on and [__] i don't even know at
this point maybe they're right
it was like exactly their reaction is
like what i'm what i'm pointing out i
think is like these
like a lot of the conservative people
often
are people who are trying to actually
protect
the more liberal they're trying to
protect the softer people they're saying
like here's a threat bro
and i ain't the type to turn away from a
threat so i'm gonna get this line you go
back in the hut
you know like i got us and and so
they actually think that they're
protecting
their families in a certain way but but
when you look at those videos when you
look at a lot of those videos from the
capitol day
like the the what what made everything
really weird to me what made me not
believe
that they actually believe it is the
[__] sitting with their feet up
on their phones or they're on instagram
live they're taking
photos like the guy taking a photo with
the security guard
um people chanting weird stuff and this
is where this is a cool jump i think
you'll
you'll like this uh hopefully i can
explain it correctly eric weinstein has
this proposition
um uh he explained it really well
actually he was on glenn beck a couple
weeks ago
and he's basically he talks about
kayfabe and kayfabe if you don't know
you probably know
uh oh uh it's the thing in
in wrestling like wwe wwf
the like that type of of of wrestling
not ufc
but it's the it's the acting part of
wrestling like when you go
you know dwayne the rock johnson he goes
out he doesn't come out as dwayne
johnson he comes out as the rock
it's this character he's created for
this second reality it's larping
it's amp guard it's you we have foam
swords
and we're playing the battle
what's going on and eric weinstein
explains this again way better than i
can but
what's actually going on is our wwe
version of what we think we're supposed
to be doing in society
is now running us it's now it's a it's a
runaway train
like these people at the capitol they're
doing this kayfabe thing
those those [__] were larping
the state capital
and what's going on imagine imagine you
and i are in the ring gabrielle and
we're fighting
and we're doing cafe and we're putting
on a show i'm doing my secret moves do
you smell what the rock is cooking we're
putting
yeah come on pumping up the crowd people
are pumped and we do a thing and i go to
armbar you
and and and and i mess up and i hit you
and i puncture one of your lungs
but we still got these people they're
looking at us we're performing
we're in this world where you can't just
you can't break character on stage bro
like
get out of here this is this is
happening you're getting paid for this
this is what
reality is right now you don't you don't
show any pain until you're backstage and
the fans can't see you
well i've punctured your lung now and
there's this thing that's going on in
our reality with our politics that we're
running the lens of our
actual um daily lived experience through
politics through this
kayfabe version this wwe version of our
actual reality it's not ufc it's wwe
it's acting you can't even say to me
like look me really in the eyes in where
in the ring you can't be like my lungs
punctured like we have to have it
my lungs punctured jake please stop turn
off your character like
take off your [__] cape and spandex
for a second my lungs punctured i'm
literally going to die
like you gotta act still you're here
like there
dude there was literally some there was
a woman who was murdered or killed she
was shot on the
capitol riots and uh eric talks about
this too again
for the for the third time he explains
way better than i can but like
he talks about this woman basically like
runs out of gun
like she she's clearly sees the gun like
she knows what's going on
and then she gets killed her life is
taken
because she's in this reality of this
kayfabe wwe like hey we're putting on
this show this is the politics thing
this is the
in in it's the this is just zooming out
from that like what i just explained
this wwe k
fabe thing that is what we are stuck in
as a culture but we're unaware to
we're unaware that we're in it for one
and we're unaware how to break it
we're unaware how abriel could possibly
communicate to me
without breaking character that her lung
is punctured and she's [__] dying
like the human thing
the thing that doesn't this doesn't
matter if the human thing and the lungs
aren't working
like that part is getting broken that
part's getting hurt we're like hurting
our
real we need to pause the show we need
to be like you guys i'm sorry everyone
like
we're dying something's going on here
we've got to take an intermission
like we got to slow down this politics
thing but we're vastly unable
to see it i i'm sorry to go off on that
on that sprint no i think i want to do
it i love it
i love it i love what you're saying and
i think that's what's going on
is that we are all in this social media
and all in this
news media and on twitter and instagram
and facebook and just like
acting the way that we think we're
supposed to act and how society wants us
to act without
stopping and realizing like what we
are as human beings and how we actually
feel
i think that's so that's such a great um
observation i think
i think that's what it is i don't know
yeah
i mean that like i feel like that's the
closest
i do i think are you cool with me using
this abriel for my
making sickness series are you we can
talk about this after but
like i would like to use this as episode
two because i feel like we
kind of did expand on some good thoughts
there
i don't know what it is but sure yeah
basically it's just i explained like
just basically
it was me and my friend spencer and i
was going to do some solo ones and like
maybe have other guests just like a part
series of
just trying to figure out what the hell
is going on and how can we solve it
without pointing fingers
making bad others how can we solve it as
like this is our culture these are our
brothers and sisters
these are our friends like why are our
uncles like uh
insufferably hard to talk to now because
they're so obsessed with
this person why are people so woke that
they don't
like they're so offended before you even
get to the start of a conversation
you know we we're so far-fetched because
we're we're in our leotards man we're in
our
wrestling boots it's uh and it's even
people who aren't on social media
like the effect of it's social media
and news media like everything because
social media bleeds into news media but
it also bleeds into just
real life and you know like my parents
aren't on social media but they absorb
the news
and they hear from my brother and i
about what's you know like we teach my
mom what a meme is and what the popular
like the
bernie mittens meme and i just send them
tons of it because they don't see it
and i'm like bernie's a meme bernie's a
meme and my mom's like
i know what this means now and so
like it comes out yeah
look at that i know what that means yeah
and so it comes it lives in our phones
and it should stay in our phones but it
comes out because
we're trying to live these identities
that we think we should be
doing and living and we see these
you know like even people
who look like they're benefiting us like
gary vee
uh grant cardone who's tony robbins like
we see these things and we're like oh
[__]
i should be an entrepreneur i should be
working on myself i should be doing
all these things you know like [__] this
person who's putting me down like i need
to care about myself i need to love
myself i need to do all this and this
first
and then we bring that out into our
experience with other people
and we're like you should care about
yourself put yourself first bro like
think about like you need to pull
yourself up and be confident
be this because like we're hearing it
from the internet and
the other people and we're really just
trying it on like
we're really just seeing this and you
know trying to act like
that's how we're supposed to act you
know like we see these people we look up
to them and
um like r.i.p um kobe bryant like the
mama mentality
we see this and we're like we should
have the mom of mentality like wake up
early do our [__] never give up all this
kind of stuff but like
if you don't have the discipline and the
type personality to be that way
be living the mamba mentality can be a
lie
for you like and then you just feel like
you're being
fake and then you're just you're you
feel it's overwhelming because you feel
like you have to do all these things and
finish them to completion and
all this kind of stuff and like maybe
that's not who you are
and not to say that's right or wrong
like for some people it doesn't work
i know like in myself i i call it my
disciplined demon
like even if i don't want to work i work
even if i don't want to go to the gym i
go
even if i don't want to do something
like
even if i don't want to wake up like
something pulls me out of bed and makes
me go like it's my disciplined demon
like i can't stop i can't quit even if i
don't like what i'm doing i have to keep
going
and it just if i'm upset no matter
what's going on in my life like i have
to push myself i will keep going i'll
always keep going it's just my
disciplined demon
some people don't have that and some
people like
look at me and they're like you're a
hard-working successful
like you're doing great for where you
are like i need to try on some of the
things that you're doing and they get
stressed out because that's not who they
are
and like we see these things we
take our social media into the world we
take
we're just seeing so much influence that
we try and take it all into the world
and we're just a bunch of people acting
like who we think we should be acting
instead of trying to figure out who we
actually are
right yeah no that's pretty powerful i
think that's exactly what's going on too
it's like um
we we we fail to realize that we truly
are
at different spots in our own paths but
that we have our own individual paths
like what
works for for me i'm always trying to
like with the podcast
i'm trying to always push people into
like what's near you like what makes
sense to you like what's going to heal
you like
i'll explain hey you know here's what
like meditation worked for me yoga
worked for me
cbd cannabis like these are things that
worked for me and i'll explain them
but i hope that what what happens is
people look for
what's what's something like that in my
own life not exactly that you know like
what's
like instead of trying to be here we go
instead of trying to be
the best you have to just try to be your
best
you know that's really simple as it is
we we
like you know look at one of the most
common words in our young
young culture now goat greatest of all
time goat
like this is the goat like he's the best
he's the best at
at what he does in his field but then
you're like how do i compare me
to these entire people in this field
like maybe you don't even [__] belong
in that field so why are you comparing
yourself
like you what you got to do is put your
head down and get to work and then
wherever you land is wherever you land
and then people can call you the goat in
your field
but that's not up to you to call
yourself you know in a way yeah
i think there's a lot of um like there's
this push right now to be an
entrepreneur and like you should start
your own business and be a hustler and
do all these kinds of things but
like if we have all these leaders
if we have so many leaders in society
like who are you leading if you have no
followers
some people are not meant to be
entrepreneurs some people are not meant
to be leaders and that's totally
okay like some people either aren't
built for it
aren't ready for it or just
that's not their place sometimes being a
follower
brings other followers and brings a
movement you know
you don't have to be a leader some you
don't have to have your own business
being an employee is not like the worst
thing that can happen to you you know
like
employment comes with benefits sometimes
but i mean like there's this push
for what i feel like our generation to
have our own companies be independent
contractors
run our own businesses become these
entrepreneurs
make our own money make a living for
ourselves and it's just like
sometimes that's not what you
should do for yourself and
you have to figure out when you say
should that
indicates an expectation so what you
should do for yourself
you have to find out what that means
like what is right for you what feels
right for you
and it's just a lot of like trying it on
if you're an entrepreneur for years and
like nothing is working
and you work for someone else and you
are living a great life feeling great
maybe that's what's right for you
you know and there are just there are
some people who are just lazy like
innately lazy and
maybe instead of kicking them in the ass
maybe we just allow them to be lazy like
i i don't want to condone that ever like
the weak and lazy part of society
i'm definitely the first one to be like
kick yourself in the ass let's go
you know like i'm a hard person like
that get your discipline demon
we're going yeah exactly stay hard like
i fight between stay hard and be
compassionate like
so stay hard
so it's just you know but
we make fun of people who are sheep but
there would be no shepherds if there
were no sheep you know
i think i think there's also
some wolves and shepherds clothing going
on too
i yeah i mean i think that
we
i don't know i mean i i guess i just
want to say like
we need to follow our our own paths
you know we need to challenge ourselves
but we need to follow our own paths i
think garyvee does do a good job of
like like he posts plenty of videos i'll
see you know he has a lot of
entrepreneur like encouraging of people
like you know
bro just like eat top ramen and work a
lot
and uh and then he'll have other times
where he's like if you don't cut it
then you don't cut it like listen what's
going on you're not meant to be co if
you're not meant to be a ceo
you know maybe and the thing is i i
think it's important to
to point out bro maybe you're a
right-hand man
like maybe yeah maybe you're the steve
wozniak you ain't steve jobs maybe
maybe you don't have to be like the
genius brick like maybe you could be
his his homie who gets his tech in the
right places or well i don't know i
don't know steve wozniak's entire
role with steve jobs but he was he was
one of the ones that helped facilitate
it like
me i'm a creative person but when it
comes to like business
and like getting things perfectly like i
struggle with all the
the the business stuff you know yeah
you got to like recognize kind of who
you are like what i mean there's things
that i i don't want to
you know stick my head in the sand and
say i'm this forever like i'm not good
at
business side of things i'm just good at
creating and i'll never be good at it
because i do want to improve these
things and try but
i'm not going to like try for the rest
of my life
and never admit to myself man i really
never got that rocking and rolling that
was just something that i was trying
that was a i was trying to fit myself
into this puzzle
and i never was that shape i was never
that shape and i couldn't admit it to
myself so true
that's so true so much of it is just
like
maybe it's just like a lack of
authenticity we're all just trying to be
this
fake version of who we think we should
be rather than trying to fit into who we
actually are
and not the undertaker we're trying to
be stone cold steve austin we're trying
to be
the rock and we're just dwayne johnson's
oh i'm embarrassed that i just just said
that actually but that's okay
i can identify with dwayne johnson
that's fine
i'll be him any day i identify as a
dwayne johnson
don't assume my in my status yeah no but
i think that's so real
like and that that goes along with all
the surface level stuff that we're
experiencing because we're just
experiencing the shell of the person
that they think they're supposed to be
right now they're upset about what they
think they're supposed to be upset about
they know what they think they're
supposed to know they're involved in all
the
channels they think they're supposed to
be involved in they follow who everyone
else follows who they think they're
supposed to be following because
we're all just trying these things on
we're going with the collective movement
everyone else is doing this thing maybe
i should be doing this thing too and
that's like a thing of human nature as
we follow the crowd
we think we are supposed to follow the
crowd when we really need to take a step
back and be like
what is all this stuff doing for me what
is it building
in myself how am i building a
personality around this
what is my identity becoming from this
you know
right yeah like what am i trying to get
from this what am i trying to gain from
this like maslow's hierarchy of needs am
i
is this how i is this how i learned that
i get love
is this how i learned that i belong is
i'm is i'm one of these people and i
agree with these things and i post these
things so i can get these likes from my
echo chambers or my tribalistic group
you know i i think that we you know
just like a young kid you talk about
childhood trauma or something they talk
about
um or even maybe not even trauma but
if you when you were a girl you threw
fits
and then that was the only time that
your mom would pick you up and take you
to the side and say
i love you honey it's okay i know i've
been showing the
your brother a lot of attention and i
know that you were the only child and
whatever and you're like oh it feels
good mom's picking me up oh yeah but
then if you you know
an emotion becomes a mood becomes a
personality if you hold on to that then
you could be this grown adult version of
like all right how do i get love
i throw a fit so mom picks me up and
says she loves me and then now you're
one of those people who like every time
you get drunk you beat the [__] out of
your boyfriend or something you know
yeah no it's it's oh my gosh i don't
know
you had me thinking of something that i
lost it but it's just so much of um
okay the mood becomes a personality but
you can turn it around
in that like if you what is the first
thing what comes before mood
motion okay so gratefulness
so you start with something gratitude
like um
building the practice of gratitude what
i've been doing
is i write down like one thing i'm
thankful for
and it's just one thing i've seen people
write five things write a whole journal
write three things whatever
but i just pick like one thing i'm
thankful for and it doesn't even have to
be something big it can be
something like you know like i'm just
thankful
i'm i have a cell phone and i'm able to
talk to you today like
literally just anything like thank
goodness you know i was
able to eat a great meal today just
whatever it is
and just doing that more
being in that i have the emotion of
gratitude from that one experience
that puts me in a better mood of more
gratitude and it's become my personality
to be more grateful
like just that little practice instead
of
when i see things and i look at the
negative about it instead i look
more for like what's the good and how
can i be grateful for it and
yes this bad thing is happening but like
look at all the great things that are
also happening around us
you know that's just that's now the way
my mind works and that's part of my
personality
yeah i really like that i actually want
to add on top of that everything you
just said pristine
but i think or not about but just add
the word practice onto it for me a
gratitude practice like i i have a
friend who we were just talking about
he's like you know i
he he doesn't fully believe i don't
think he has like a
religious denomination or whatever but
he's like he's like lately when i lay
down in bed like the last couple months
has been helping me a lot with stress
i pray i just i go over the things that
i'm grateful for and i
it doesn't pray as in like god please
give me these things or whatever he just
kind of talks to
you know whoever might be listening in
his head or you know whatever and he
brings up gratitude and he brings up you
know things that he's excited about
that are going to happen in his life and
and when he says it helps him a lot
and so i think a gratitude practice is
very helpful and i think we can all
benefit from that instead of spending
you know
uh 45 of your waking hours looking
through the window of
like catastrophic events that and as
msnbc has told you that are important
you need to look around and look like
your your lens needs to be just your
eyes
and your window needs to be your eyes
you know to look around and say like
what am i grateful for like wow like
what a what a blessing that i have
like a podcast where i can have these
open conversations what a blessing that
i have
this room like what like what a what a
wonderful spot for a creator like me to
to be able to make art here like wow i
have like you know very expensive dj
equipment and like i you know i know how
to use it wow like i'm so grateful for
that
so i think a practice of like noticing
oh i've been in a bad mood or
i've been watching a lot of news or ooh
i've been whatever and then instead
saying
i need to negate that i need to um
do less of that and do more of this and
the gratitude just
just being grateful for the the things
in your surroundings and then one more
thing um
meta meta loving kindness meditation so
you can learn this sam harris has a
has the app waking up um it's i think
it's like 114 a year but if all you have
to do if you want it for free
um is you just you just email them and
no questions asked they'll give you the
app the app for a free year
so waking up app and he has a whole um
helped me greatly because i
am someone who gets caught in obsessive
loops so
uh meta practice you literally go and
it's a 10 minute meditation and you
focus on your breathing
and um and then you slowly just bring up
uh you know people in your life like you
know you bring up someone like
you don't have a complicated
relationship with you bring up just like
wow what's one of my good friends
and then you just kind of oh try to like
visualize them try to think about like
what
is you know your your good childhood
buddy like
name him cool yeah he's naming your head
and you're like oh yeah i love that
[__] like he's awesome you know
we've had some good times together maybe
think of some memories
and you think of you start envisioning
your friends smiling you know and the
guy in meditation walks you through
these sort of things
all right bring another person in your
life like um you don't go for anybody
difficult if you've dealt with any
trauma or anything like that can come
later but
um and it calms you and so what happens
in these is
you actually like you'll have kind of
releases in your body of like huh
and you'll kind of feel these rushes of
of warmth like it's
and these are biochemical responses
happening like so
you can practice gratitude and feel
physical changes in your body whereas
you know when we're mad there's a
physical change in our body we get all
tensed up the same thing we get when
we're cold our shoulders hunch up i mean
huh
when you're mad these things happen
you're allowing a physical fear response
to happen within your body by
[__] fox news but you're not willing
to
to sit down for 10 minutes a day and and
allow the thoughts of the people who
have brought love in
in you your ability to be grateful for
them to bring them up
and it really um yeah basically
meta loving kindness meditation it's
fantastic i highly recommend it for
anybody
you literally feel inner releases and in
inner
inner warmth um sometimes they could
take like a couple days in a row
if you're really kind of you know been
out there for me it's taking a couple
days where i'm like ah
i guess i feel kind of better but then
consecutively a few days
you know on your fifth day you're like
oh my god i think i just
this is what jesus feels like i feel so
wonderful right now and i love my
friends so much i'm gonna [__] call
all of them
you know you're like it's it's just this
high of gratitude
and i think gratitude can heal
so much of what's going on in the world
i really do
i always i like to look at my life sort
of
in the entire spectrum of my life
so like i see myself as a 26 year old
now
but like i see myself as all the
experience i've had
and all the experience i'm going to have
and don't know about
and so like when i'm upset in a
situation i'm always looking for like
how will this affect my future and where
is this feeling coming from from my past
and i feel like that helps me a lot
to sort of like take myself out of the
situation
and be like let's look at this you know
like when i get into arguments with
somebody
i look at the entirety of our friendship
and i'm like
where where did this come from and how
is it going to affect us moving forward
and when we move forward
what are we going to look back on this
and like see it as
and i i do that in the moment i'm i'm
fortunate enough to like
be able to see things that way because i
see like in my relationship
i see the entirety of my relationship i
see where it came from
and hopefully where it's going and what
is this conversation
right now like going like when we look
back on it like what is it going to
look like in the future and
i just think of like a lot of my
gratitude
comes from being able to objectively
look at my life like just step back
and be like here's where i am in this
lifespan here's where i am things are
pretty good
like there's some bumpiness along the
road but like
thank goodness for all of that and like
i'm such in a good place now
that i that the rest of my life i'm sure
will be pretty good because
i have the outlook of it being pretty
good even when
bad things happen like things are still
pretty good
even like like i don't even want to say
it but even when my parents pass away
like
my life is still pretty good like i've
still i
really i don't even know like i could
lose my apartment and lose my family and
lose my relationship and lose my cats
but like
at least i still have my friends maybe i
lose all my friends at least i still
have my health
at least i still have the ability to
figure things out you know
there's just number one it's not so
serious and number two like
the lifespan is so long the experience
of right now is so short and like to be
able to look at it and be like this is
so bad and so stressful and this is so
negative it's just like but look at all
of these experiences
and what is this one doing for you right
now
and i don't i don't see how
people can't be grateful and
how we can just live in these shells of
who we think we should be for society
yeah we keep living as our kayfabe
characters
our wwe representations of ourselves
yeah i think that is very important to
remember
that's something you and i both do that
not a lot of people do
is it is going meta
on your own life essentially like like
able to
pull up the fact that like
loss right now hurts and it's pain and
emotions are real and and like
agonizing and you know often very
intense and very hard to like
think of more than just this moment in
this pain that i'm experiencing but
when you really go meta and you back up
you can
you can remember like oh you know
i okay just as a low-hanging fruit
example
you know if your friend passed away
like what you remember you're of course
sad like you don't get to have any more
memories with him
but what what is with the reason why
you're so sad is because you have
already had
many memories with them and it's not
about being able to hold them and take
them and bring them somewhere or
anything or you can have them for
infinity and you get to
bury them with you when you're dead or
whatever it's like that is what life
has been that is what your life is is
those experiences that you had with your
friend with your companions with the
loved ones with the people around your
family you're
like like we we
mourn for the loss of our
comfortability in the moment and that
overshadows and really puts this dark
ugly shadow on the beauty of
our lengthy ass lives you know like if i
like
if if i die tomorrow you know like
man i've experienced some great things
like i hope i get a lot more years you
know it's the same reason why we're
we're we're upset when a young person
dies when one young child dies because
we're like
man he didn't even get to he didn't even
get to have a 12 year old best friend
yet
you know and he passed away that is
terrible but we've got to realize why
why we'd be angry you know or an older
person you're like oh you know he'd live
oh he's ready to go he's happy he's he's
fulfilled you know he's going out with a
smile on his face yeah he lived a good
life you know it's
it's we're always trying to take stock
of of the right now
um and say that that's us but we've got
to be able to expand on our lives and
say like what is this whole thing what
have i been able to experience so i love
what you just said
we mourn for the com we mourn for our
comfortability in the moment i wrote it
down i love that
i that's so so true and it's
when we step back and look at our entire
life
like that pain was
necessary to push us to this next step
that we can see because
when we pull back we can see our entire
life and all of our experiences
that bump in the road was so important
and it was so important for us
we went so low and in the moment like we
felt so bad but it was so necessary for
us to feel that way
because then we moved to this point and
this point had all of these effects
and it's just i agree we mourn for our
comfortability and
comfortability in the moment but when we
pull back and see it like some of it is
so
all of it is so necessary our experience
of life
is so necessary and to be able to feel
it experience it and see it for what it
really is
in the lens of our whole lifespan like
it's so important
and god my gosh it would help so many
people if they thought that way
this i i feel like i'm just hearing i've
listened to a lot of ram toss i'm just
hearing his voice go
um um like
oh man i almost lost it uh
that that's just your dharma or or that
that's just your dominant like that is
that's your life that's
that's this is what it is like don't
don't you get it like this is there
isn't more than this this is
this is the thing like we think we're
getting somewhere we're gonna catch this
carrot on a stick
but it's not there it's never been there
this is it this is the thing
right now it's so true like your dharma
stressing about whatever is happening
and when does it get easier
and when does this and when does that
just you have to figure it out how to
make it easy now
like what you're going through like you
need to navigate it now because it
doesn't get
easier you feel the pain and understand
how to
deal with it and that's what makes it
easier like feeling your life is what
makes it easier not numbing yourself
from the experiences that you are
inevitably going to have
yeah yeah like reaching numbing yourself
from that experience that goes right
back to that comfortability like where
you know ooh my interior is feeling pain
right now so like how can i be
most comfortable i mean i've i have my
own addictions for sure and i have had
them even worse with other things in the
past and
like i know exactly how that goes it's
like so many layers deep you're starting
to feel something
and you just say oh how can i be more
comfortable in this moment rather than
how can i assure that i live a fully 360
degree
lived fulfilled life you know we want to
be comfortable right now
that means we're always trying to get
somewhere and then we realize at the end
like oh [__]
i forgot to look over my shoulder this
whole time like oh dang
80 years you know oh damn i forgot to
look back and be grateful you know
gratitude is probably one of the most
important things um i i was thinking
we're getting pretty up here in time i
appreciate you
you hanging with me i don't know if you
have anywhere else to be but i was
thinking um
um also i apologize for not asking your
time frame before we got going that's
unprofessional for me too
um but i i was curious the first thing
that you wrote down on your paper that
we started with
can we loop back to that is that
sensible what what did it say again
is that a good way to wrap this up a
majority of the human experience is
relaying
and relating to people and i don't feel
like we're doing that
so yes that comes from
we are not relating to people because we
are
acting as who we think we should be
rather than acting as who we are and
when we are not
who we are in ourselves we are not able
to connect with anyone else oh my god
i'm dropping the mic mic drop
that is so dope isn't that wow yeah
that's you know i've i've talked about
how
with these arguments you know left right
i'm this
i'm that i'm blue i'm red or whatever
like these arguments
they do have this innate it's hard to
put your finger on but it's like
are you guys making eye contact or are
you yelling
above each other's heads like you know
what i mean like they're not
you're like oh man you're just missing
the the person stuff though
you know and that's what it is we're
we're we have these little like
like a little pokemon above our head and
like my blastoise is trying to shoot at
your venusaur
but like we got to forget that we're not
the [__] pokemon we're not pokemon
trainers man we're humans pretending to
be pokemon trainers
yeah exactly you know it's so true and
it definitely comes back to that
we are our human experience
is defined by how we relate to other
people
because it helps us define ourselves
and if we're too busy
acting like people who we aren't we
don't
figure out who we are and aren't able to
actually connect with anybody wow
it's time for collective healing y'all
dude oh man i love how that came full
circle i feel like that was like just
it was so good just pristine um
gabrielle thank you so much for doing
this thank you for your time i'm totally
gonna use this for my sense making
sickness series
um i'll send you the link to the other
one and we'll talk about this after but
um
thank you for stumbling it's like
allowing me to stumble through thank you
for
opening up thank you for being awesome
thank you for being my friend you're
just awesome person anyway i love like
having these
talks with you we get going pretty good
with we'll get texting and messaging
back and forth with a lot of these
concepts
um so it's always nice to actually talk
yeah dude it is and then you know i i
feel like the
the zoom calls i'm always a little butt
hurt i'm always like it's not as good as
in person i can't really connect with
them but
i mean after just a few minutes you know
it's it's just a normal it's it feels
it's pretty authentic it feels feels
nice it's okay
i think so too and i appreciate you jake
you're always the person who i feel like
i can authentically go to
and like relate to and it's because we
have that
just like we're not trying to be any
facade of any other people to each other
like we are just
i always ask you about your human
experience and
we that's what we talk about yeah i
appreciate that about you
yeah thank you abriel i mean and you
even like working with me to where you
have to be like
jake here's your deadline you have to
like you have to hit hit the business
side of me
and you have to like reign in this you
have to reign in creators which is just
a wonderful
like a job you have a gift for for sure
um but yeah we can meet each other on on
all these levels and
it's awesome and so i'm glad that we
covered a lot of things that we covered
today
um i think i asked you last time what
the world needs more of right now right
i think i
i ended up the world needs more
authenticity more compassion more
understanding
that's what i want to see more of
understanding yourself
being compassionate to yourself
like allowing yourself to feel feelings
allowing yourself to struggle allowing
yourself to take a day off from the gym
allowing yourself to skip in your diet
you know just like
be wrong yeah be wrong be wrong
like it's okay you're not right about
everything be wrong be silly be
ridiculous be annoying like be whatever
you want to be like be whatever you
are and understand that and then bring
that understanding to other people and
just spread that
understanding kindness compassion
authenticity
transparency vulnerability all the
things okay would you rather fight
a horse sized duck or
a hundred duck-sized horses
um i'll go with a horse-sized duck
because a hundred duck-sized horses
all have hooves i mean
like like imagine how heavy one
horse-sized duck would truly be
i'd still how would you fight that
have you thought about this don't you
lay awake at night wondering about this
dude
i think i'm gonna go with the one enemy
rather than a hundred little enemies
i don't know there was an episode of uh
something
um i don't know what it was oh uh
some anime thing that my boyfriend was
watching and it was
fighting this enemy that he couldn't see
it was a very small thing and
i think i'd rather fight something i can
see that's very large a big target
big moving target i know where my target
is i'll go with the horse-sized duck
feathers
all right respect if i ever if i ever
encounter a horse-sized duck i'm calling
you up
let me ask you what what do i do man
don't don't um bank on me having the
answer
and you're like jake are you on lsd
right now
that'll be my first question all right
man i appreciate it listeners take care
of yourself
drink some water love yourself practice
gratitude practice compassion
and thank you for hanging with us if you
if you hung up
hung with us this far check out
gabrielle i'll link a couple of her
things then
we also have another podcast together
for more of her like personal life and
in her work so check that out as well
um have a good day abriel i'll talk to
you right after this
do we learn how to have better
conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
but how could we make better sense of it
[Music]
all
you